你是谁
Who are you?
我是你最可怕的噩梦
I'm your worst nightmare that's who I am.
我他妈在和你说话 听到了吗
I'm talkin' to you! that's who!
该死的 我一点也不在乎
What? I don't give a damn!
你侵犯了小企业主
You're violatin' the most basic
最神圣的基本权利
and sacred rights of a small-business owner.
我们说的只是个孩子
We're talkin' about a kid
他根本无力和你抵抗
who doesn't have means to fight you.
下地狱去吧 你这混蛋
I'm gonna bury you, you motherfucker.
你在威胁我吗
You threatenin' me?
嘿 有本事当面说
Hey, do it to my face.
拿笔记下
You got a pen?
我在春季街75号 八层
We're at 75 spring street, eighth floor.
来吧 让我们拭目以待
Come on by. We validate.
也很高兴和你对话 议员先生
Good talkin' to you, too, senator.
- 喂 喂 - 你好
- Hey. Hey. - What? Hey.
- 嘿 我在和你说话 - 我知道
- Hey, I'm talkin' to you. - yeah.
呃
Uh...
我是理查德
I'm Richard.
我不是故意偷听的 很抱歉
I'm sorry I was listening.
我无意冒犯你 我不是那种人
I didn't mean to be rude. I wasn't raised like that.
你说话都以 我 开头吗
You always start every sentence with "I"?
我
I'm...
对不起 先生 我是新来的
I'm sorry, sir. I'm the new...
我负责补给办公用品
I'm the supply room clerk.
偷听我讲电话
Eavesdropping on me?
不是的 先生
No, sir.
很好 我要一些胶带 帮我拿一下
Well, good. I need some more tape, so get on that.
呃 胶带的话
Yeah, about that.
您可以看下第二层抽屉 先生
You're gonna wanna check the second drawer down, sir.
有胶带和一盒新的签字笔
Tape and a new box of pens.
我之前看到快用完了
I saw you were runnin' low.
什么意思
What's that?
您再看看下一层抽屉
You might wanna check the next drawer down.
最底下那个
The one on the bottom.
你怎么知道我喜欢士力架
How'd you know I like snickers?
呃
Uh...
因为我之前看到
I knew you liked them 'cause I saw
垃圾桶里的包装纸
You had the wrappers in your trash can.
别翻我的垃圾桶
Don't go in my trash.
没人能翻我的垃圾桶 你叫什么名字
Nobody goes in my trash. What's your name?
理查德 朱维尔
Richard Jewell.
从今天起 我就叫你雷达了
From now on, I'm gonna call you radar.
像 风流军医俏护士 那样吗
Like from M*a*s*h?
走吧
Get out.
你这儿的兄弟都蛮厉害啊
Pretty tough crowd you're runnin' with here.
搞得我进来都有点紧张
Got a little nervous comin' in.
您还好吗 先生
How you doin', sir?
别担心 我也常来这儿
Don't worry, all right. I come here often.
喔 玩的不错嘛 雷达
Whoo. nice shootin', radar.
谢谢夸奖 这其实是 呃
Thank you. this is actually kind of like, uh...
为我将来去执法部门
Kind of like practice for my future
做演习
In law enforcement.
亚特兰大警局 联邦调查局 也许是特务机关
APD, FBI, maybe secret service.
你怎么想去那种地方
What the hell would you wanna do that for?
因为我信仰为民而战 先生
'cause I believe in protecting people, sir.
每天晚上我都研究刑法条例
I study the penal code every night.
听起来是很热血的夜晚呢
Sounds like a humdinger of a night.
- 漂亮 - 噢
- Yes! - Oh.
还不错啊 新手的运气罢了
Yeah, it's not bad. You got some beginner's luck.
9700分怎么了
Yeah, what's wrong with 9,700?
诶 对第一次来说 算可以了
Eh, nothing's wrong with it for a first time.
第一次 行 我们再来一局
First time? All right, come on, let's go.
他们只给我30分钟吃午饭
Oh. They only give me, like, 30 minutes for lunch.
我得马上回去了
I gotta head back in a minute.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你就说和我在一起
You can say you're with me.
开始吧
Let's get it on.
呃好吧 不管了
Oh, shoot. All right.
- 准备好了没 - 好了 先生
- You ready? - Yes, sir.
让我看看你有什么能耐 神枪手
Let's see what you got, hotshot.
好 我也要动真格的了
Yeah, I mean business, too.
- 是吗 - 你试过单手射击吗
- Yeah? - You ever do it with one hand?
布莱恩特先生
Mr. Bryant?
我的天
Oh, Jesus Christ.
不好意思
Sorry.
现在有点忙 不太方便 所以
I'm a little busy. Not a good time, so...
- 呃 - 迟点说
- Yeah... - Talk later?
我知道你很忙
I know you're busy.
我只是想 呃
I just wanted to...
过来告诉你
Come by to let you know,
我要离开这里了
I'm not gonna be workin' here anymore.
来和你告别
Came to say bye.
找到一份新工作 做保安
Got a new job doin' security.
- 好吧 - 明天就报道了
- Okay. - So, that starts tomorrow.
不错 嘿 很高兴认识你
All right. Hey, good to see you.
我想在走之前给你一样东西
I wanted to give you something before I leave.
表示感谢
Just to say thank you.
好吧 呃
Hey, okay. uh...
谢谢
Thank you.
我看到没剩多少了
I noticed you were runnin' low.
没事了
All right.
嘿 过来一下
Hey, come here.
- 怎么了 - 你钱够用吗
- What? - You got enough money?
应该够吧 怎么了
Yeah, I guess so. Why do you... why do you ask?
这代表着 来而不往非礼也
This comes with a quid pro quo.
你知道是什么意思吗
You know what that is?
知道 是拉丁语的 等价交换
Yes, sir. Quid pro quo is Latin. "This for that."
没错 这就是我和你之间的等价交换
That's right. Well, this comes with a quid pro quo.
相当公平 我们来做个交易
Fair exchange. so, here's the deal.
等你当上警察后
When you get your badge
我相信会有那么一天的
And I can see that day's comin',
答应我别变成一个混蛋
Don't become an asshole.
你明白吗
You got me?
当然 先生 我不会变成坏人
No, sir, I won't become an asshole.
人一旦拥有哪怕一点权利
A little power can turn a person
都可能变成魔鬼 理查德
Into a monster, Richard.
别做那种人
Don't do that.
明白吗
Do you understand?
好的 嗯
Yeah. um...
我会在拿到第一笔薪水的时候
Yeah, I'm gonna get that back to you
还给你的 先生
The first paycheck I get, sir.
连同利息
I'm gonna pay you back
一起还给你
with interest.
好 没问题
Okay. You do that.
谢谢您 布莱恩特先生
Thank you, Mr. Bryant.
她说她玩足球
She said that she played soccer.
我当时就说
So I was like,
怎么 你想看看我怎么用脚
"You wanna see me, what, balance
让一瓶啤酒保持平衡吗
A frickin' beer on my foot?"
老天 你这白痴
God, you dumb-ass.
我只是慌了 快去开门
I got flustered. Get the door.
等等
Wait.
反应挺快 小伙子
Nice try, hotshot.
是那个菜鸟警察
It's that rent-a-cop.
妈的
Shit.
开门吧 给他开门
Open the door. Open the door.
有事吗 警官
Yes, officer?
有人投诉这里噪音太大
I heard a little noise complaint.
我来看看什么情况
Thought I'd come take a look around.
你得先有搜查令
You're gonna need a search warrant first.
小伙子 把你的手拿开
Son, you're gonna have to take your hands off me.
我只是看看而已
I'm just takin' a little look-see.
首先 你都算不上真正的警察
Well, you're not even a real cop, first of all,
而且你不能没有搜查令
And you're not allowed
就进别人的房间
to search a room without a warrant.
- 小伙子 - 我们付了房租的
- Boy! - We pay rent. We pay rent.
所以这是我们的地方 老兄
It's like we live here, man.
孩子 这是我的职责
Boy, this is my job.
你必须配合我的工作 小伙子
I'm gonna have to have you let me do my job, curlicue.
可这是我们的房间
And this is our room.
没错
Yeah.
你知道有个概念叫
Are you aware of the notion
非法搜查和扣押吗
of unlawful search and seizure?
混蛋 你不能就这样走进别人的房间
Asshole, you're not supposed to just walk in here.
你就推我 试探我的底线吧
Keep pushin' me. Keep testin' me.
看你喜不喜欢这带来的后果
See if you like where it gets you.
是吗
Yeah?
你没事吧
You all right?
我在新生入学周是怎么说的
What did I say freshman orientation week?
我说 校园内不许喝酒
I said, "no drinkin' on my campus."
我不知道为什么之前没人提醒我
I don't know why no one called my attention
留意你的档案
to your file before.
有很多人投诉你的工作
I mean, all these complaints about you.
殴打学生
Physically assaulting a student.
还有 你真的有在公路上
And have you really been pulling people over
把别人的车拦下吗
on the highway?
呃 是的先生
Um... yes, sir, I have.
我只是觉得在路上检查醉驾
I figured that if you do the drunk tests on the road,
校园内会安全很多
trouble never gets to the campus.
公路不在我们的管辖范围之内
We don't have any jurisdiction on the highway.
我明白 但
And I realize that,
我信仰法律和秩序 先生
but I believe in law and order, sir.
一个国家不能没有法律和秩序
You can't have a country without it.
嗯 你被哈伯沙姆县
Hmm. and you were dismissed
治安办公室解雇了
From the Habersham county sheriff's office.
我不希望这里有任何
"I don't want any mickey-mousin'
对工作敷衍了事的人
on these grounds."
这不是你说过的话吗
Isn't that what you said?
我什么时候说过
When did I say that?
去年校庆的时候 我记得
You said it at founders' day last year, I believe.
您当时在供应酒水的地方
You were by the punch bowl.
我走向你 然后你对我说
I walked up to you, and you said to me...
嗯 呃
Uh, uh...
我当时打断了您的讲话
Well, I had interrupted you.
我道歉后 开始向你介绍自己
I apologized, I introduced myself,
我说 我会成为你手下
And I said I was gonna be the greatest
最尽责的校园保安
Campus security guard you ever had.
然后你说 很好
And you said, "that's good."
我不希望这个校园里
"I don't want any mickey-mousin'
有任何敷衍了事的人
on this campus."
我好像还把它写下来了
I think I might've even wrote it down.
我会记录很多东西
I write down most things.
把重要的都记下来
I keep the important ones.
我记得 噢 在这里
And I believe... oh, yes, sir.
我不希望这个校园里
"I don't want any mickey-mousin'
有任何敷衍了事的人
on these grounds."
这是你曾说过的话 先生
Those are your words, sir.
我把它看得很重要
So, I took it seriously,
现在我想问您的是
And now, my question for you is,
那些住校的孩子们
What about these kids in the dormitory,
喝酒 还做其他事
drinkin' and all that?
您打算采取什么措施吗 还是就这样算了
What you gonna do about that? We're just gonna let it slide?
你想自己辞职
Do you wanna resign,
还是我把你炒掉
or would it be better if I fired you?
接着我走进那家伙的办公室
So, I'm goin' into this guy's office
想着他把我叫过来
and I think that he's bringing me in there,
是要表扬我的工作 你懂的
'cause he's gonna, you know, give me some commendation
或者升职什么的
or a promotion or something.
结果发现是为了炒我鱿鱼
Come to find out he brought me in there to fire me.
你能相信吗
Can you believe that?
反正都是些烂工作
Well, it was a shit job, anyway.
学校里那帮兔崽子
Hasslin' college brats.
而且还会有很多安保工作的
Besides, there's gonna be so much security work
过几个月 你会找到新工作的
The next couple months, you're set.
是吧 我工作很努力的
Yeah, well, I worked hard at that job.
只是那帮孩子太顽皮了
Those kids were just runnin' wild.
奥运会马上要开始了 哥们
Olympics are coming, brother.
你可以保卫这该死的整个世界
You can police the whole damn world.
在世纪公园举办庆典
Celebrations at centennial park.
- 噢 - 这该死的城市
- oh. - something finally happens
终于有正经事可做了
In this stupid city
我却要去什么狗屁肯尼 罗杰斯演唱会
And I get a fucking Kenny Rogers concert.
已经算好了 总好过马术比赛
It could be worse. Could be equestrian.
我还要做丰胸手术
I'm getting my tits done.
我看不出这两者有什么联系
I don't see how that applies here.
明年这个时候 我们都会在电视上
This time next year, we're all gonna be
求着别人给我们工作做
scrambling for jobs on TV.
升到D杯 怎么样
What do you think, D cup?
我会想你的 凯西 但我想他们不会
Well, I'd miss you, Kathy, but, I don't think they would.
小姐们 很抱歉我超有料的谋杀报道
Ladies, I'm sorry my hot-ass murders
把你们那些无聊的废话从头版上挤下来
keep knocking your boring bullshit off the front page.
真不好意思呢
I'm so sorry.
你想喝一杯吗
You wanna get a drink?
我会拖你后腿的
I'd just slow you down.
随你便
Suit yourself.
没问题 如果你觉得这样最好的话
Yeah, if you think that's the best thing.
很好
Great.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
我要去世纪公园了
I get to go to centennial park.
沃森
Watson.
怎么
Yeah.
我们没有碳粉和复印纸了
We're out of toner and copy paper.
呃
Um...
然后呢
Okay.
我去买的话 你就得接这里的电话
If I go, you'll have to answer the phones.
不 我去
No, I'll go.
商场在大减价 打九折
There's a sale at the mall. It's 10% off,
但得说出一个美国奥运队里的名字
if you name anyone from the U.S. Olympic team.
噢 乐到不行
Oh, joy.
我知道 人们要连着笑十六天
I know. People smiling for 16 days.
你应该觉得很难受
It's going to be awful for you.
不 对有线新闻网和可口可乐
No, it's gonna be wonderful for CNN,
还有那些有钱佬来说 应该爽翻了
coca-cola, and anybody with a parking lot.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
这一天真的来了
It's really here.
是啊 妈妈
Yeah, this is it, mama.
要是我在奥运会上表现好了
I do this Olympics gig well
说不定又能做回警察
Maybe someone might make me a cop again.
再过几天 他会努力成为
He, in a few days will try
第一个赢得奥运金牌的人
to become the first man to ever win Olympic gold...
是啊 尽你所能就好了
Yeah, you just do the best you can.
嘿 我应该会在你
Hey, I might not move out
做完手术后才搬出去
Until after you've had your surgery.
我也许能帮上什么
You might need me for something.
- 你觉得呢 - 噢
- What do you think? - Oh...
你先去上班吧
You go on now.
奥运会结束后
We got plenty of time to tend to that
有的是时间处理这件事
After the games are over.
别开车太快
No heavy foot of yours drivin' there.
慢慢来
No heavy foot.
慢点开车 好的妈妈
No heavy foot. Yes, ma'am.
为什么呢
And why is that?
因为你要等到保险额增加 才能让我出事
Because you'll kill me if the insurance goes up?
没错 到那时我就得杀了你
That's right. I'd have to kill you.
你得杀了我
You'd have to kill me.
嘿 呃
Hey, uh...
尽管我只负责看管
It's still law enforcement, ain't it?
看管一些音响设备 架子什么的
Even if I'm just watching over
我还是在执行法务 对吗
A bunch of stereo equipment and whatnot?
废话 当然是
Heck yeah.
你一直都是个好人
You're still the good guy
对抗那些坏人 不是吗
Wardin' off the bad guys, aren't ya?
回头见 妈妈
I'll see you later, mother.
去公园转转吧 你在家会无聊死的
Come on down to the park you get bored with yourself.
工作顺利
Have fun.
默罕默德 阿里
Muhammad ali,
奥运会选手 本名卡修斯 克莱
Of course an Olympian, as young Cassius Clay,
是1960年罗马奥运会拳击项目金牌得主
Gold medal boxer, 1960, the games of rome.
多么震撼的时刻
What a moment.
1996年
The opening
亚特兰大百年奥运会的开幕式
of the 1996 centennial Olympic games in Atlanta.
随便放吧 谢了兄弟
Anywhere's fine. Thanks, man.
没事儿
Yeah.
别客气
No trouble.
- 你们还需要什么吗 - 没有了 谢谢
- You guys need anything else? - No, thanks.
还需要什么的话 告诉我就好
Y'all guys need anything, give me a holler.
- 你离得很近了 - 是啊 我知道
- You're up close and personal. - Yeah, I know.
你看到他了吗 他就在那儿
You see him? He's right there.
我不敢相信 肯尼·罗杰斯就在这儿
I can't believe it's Kenny Rogers!
嘿 Tom
Hey, Tom.
哟 哈喽 Kathy
Well, well, well. Hello, Kathy.
欢迎来到地球上最快乐的地方
Welcome to the happiest place on earth.
简直是噩梦
Fucking nightmare.
没有地方在犯罪吗
Isn't there anything crime-y goin' on anywhere?
我在这 我怎么知道
How would I know? I'm here.
简直了
Christ.
想跳舞吗
You wanna dance?
我想啊 但我在执勤
I'd love to, but I am on duty.
执什么勤 来一起啊
Oh, fuck duty. Come on.
不如跳舞
Might as well.
女士 不好意思
Excuse me, ma'am.
你要水吗
You, uh, need some water?
水 今晚有点闷热
Water. It's a warm night.
这是随便送的吗
Are you just giving 'em away?
是的 我是留给警官的
Yeah, I keep 'em in here for police officers,
或者怀着小宝宝的女士
Or when I see a pregnant woman.
- 谢谢 - 没事
- Thanks. - Yeah.
- 玩得开心 - 你也是
- You have a good night. - You, too.
不好意思 让一下
Excuse me, sorry.
那群运动员都在抱怨
You got all these athletes complaining about
因为交通拥堵 迟到赛场
Getting to the venues late on account of the traffic.
我们警察也哪都去不了
But what about the cops? We can't get anywhere, either.
昨晚我真的拉着警笛
I had half a mind to run my siren last night
才能到超市
just to get to the supermarket.
真的太挤了
so damn crowded.
城市规划太差了
It's just poor planning by the city.
没有一个人
There ain't a one of them jake-legs
对交通情况有任何概念
got a damn clue about traffic patterns.
- 没错 - 理查德 你怎么看
- Yeah. yeah. - What do you think, Richard?
市政府的人是不是一群傻子
Think the city's a bunch of jake-legs?
我不知道诶
I don't know.
我觉得要协调那些交通
I think, you know, it's hard coordinating all this
也挺难的
And marta and all that.
还好不是我来规划这些
I'm glad I don't have to do it.
什么鬼
Come on.
怎么了
What?
规划好那些交通运输
It's tough, doin' all the logistics,
确实很难啊
And gettin' everything right.
那个梳马尾的人
You see that guy over there with the ponytail?
你们之前有见过吗
Y'all ever seen him before?
没有
No.
你们觉得他的背包 是不是有点奇怪
Does his backpack look funny to you?
哪里奇怪
Funny how? hmm?
马上看不见他了 我一会回来
Now, I'm losin' him now. I'll be back, guys.
抱歉 先生
Excuse me, sir?
来点冰啤酒
Hey, man, how about a cold one?
谢了 兄弟
Oh! Hey, brother, thanks.
干了
Cheers, dude.
美 利 坚
USA! USA! USA!
棒
Yes!
天呐
Jesus Christ.
你上头了吧
You forgot the move.
来啊
Oh, come on,
你为啥跟个木头似的
Why so grim, big guy?
因为很无聊啊
Because I'm bored.
- 太无聊了 - 我们都很无聊
- It's boring. - We're all bored.
这些人就不觉得无聊
These guys aren't bored.
这个跳舞是认真的吗
I mean, this dance is a real thing, huh?
我觉得我值得
I just feel like I was made
更好的
for something better, you know, than this?
你不觉得我也是吗
Yeah, you think I wasn't?
就有更多时间来回忆
To have a little more time to reflect.
我在写一本书 不是关于我自己的
I'm writing a book right now, not about myself...
天呐 他真是太帅了
My, my, he sure is handsome.
你确定不要三明治什么的吗
You sure you don't want a sandwich or anything?
不用了妈妈 我胃不太舒服
No, mama, I'm not feelin' well. It's my stomach.
是吃坏肚子了吗
Something you ate?
可能是吧
Yeah, I guess so.
我一早上都在厕所里
I was in the bathroom all morning.
你为什么要吃垃圾食品
Why you eat that fast food junk?
理查德 你怎么回事
What is wrong, Richard?
妈妈 我只是突然发现
I just look around this place and I just think
这世界欠你太多
The world owes you better than this, mama.
咳 这世界欠我们俩的
Shoot, the world owes us both.
但生活就是这样
This is what we got.
去上班吧 儿子
Go do your job, son.
要死了
Oh, god.
好了 别想了
Okay, now.
喲 亚特兰大
Yo, Atlanta!
你们感觉怎么样
How you feelin'?
你们好吗 说好哦
You feelin' all right? say, "yeah!"
听
Listen.
这可能也是好事
This could be a good thing.
怎么会是好事
How's this a good thing?
我们可以带你去潜水池
Oh, we could bring you out to the diving venue.
让你用屁放国歌
We could have you fart the national anthem.
现在别让我笑
Do not make me laugh right now.
你要不跟别人换个班 回家吧
Why don't you switch shifts with someone? Go home.
这是我最爱的乐队
This is my favorite band.
杰克·马克 是你最爱的乐队
Jack Mack is your favorite band?
我不走 我没事
I'm not leavin'. I'm fine.
行行行
All right.
我一会就回
I'll be right back.
去吧
Go.
- 妈妈你看 我是克丽·斯特鲁格 - 再来一遍
- Look, mom, I'm KerrI Strug. - Do that again.
可以啊 你是谁
Nice. Who are you?
爸爸你看 我是米奇·盖洛
Dad, look, I'm Mitch Gaylord.
你好厉害
That's awesome.
走 吃冰淇淋去
Come on, let's go get some ice cream.
好了 别表演体操了
Okay, guys, enough gymnastics.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你们最好现在
Y'all better stop what you're doing.
别搞事情
Right now.
怎么 肥猪也管事
What's goin' on, lard and in charge?
太逗了
This fuckin' guy!
怎么 你要切断我手机信号吗
Yeah, what are you gonna do, cancel my phone service?
我告诉你们
Yeah, let me tell you somethin', hotshot.
警察就不会这么好声好气了
The police, they're not gonna ask you as nicely.
他们看到酒鬼 搞事情的
They see the drunk and disorderly,
直接就把你们抓起来关一夜
That's cuffs and a night in the lockup.
他在威胁我们
He's threatening us.
你得先跑起来抓住我 肥猪
You're gonna have to catch me first, lard-ass.
小伙子 你觉得你跑得比警车快是吗
You think you're faster than a cop car, son?
当然
Yeah.
你能跑那么快吗
You think you're that fast, roadrunner?
当然 我是迈克尔·约翰逊
Yeah, I'm Michael Johnson, okay?
地球上最快的男人
The fastest man on earth.
你要看我的金牌吗
You wanna see my medals?
他有金牌 他会给你看
He's got medals. He'll show 'em to you.
- 我给你看 - 他会证明的
- I can show 'em to you. - He'll prove it.
你去哪儿
Dude, where are you going?
别走啊
Oh, come on.
你们等着
You just wait. You wait.
好嘞 再见了您
Yeah, yeah, bye-bye.
谁把这么大个包落下了
Who the fuck left this monstrosity?
- 好像 - 特种部队
- it's like some... - G.I. joe.
很重啊
It's heavy.
我们应该带走
I think we should take it.
我也觉得
Yes.
不好意思
Excuse me.
同志们 那边有几个酒鬼
Hey, guys. We got some drunk guys
用酒瓶子砸塔
breakin' bottles against the tower.
他们不听我的
They're not listenin' to me.
他们应该会听你们的
Maybe they'll listen to you.
大家都怕警徽
People respect the badge.
我们应该带去蓝调之家
I think we should take it down to the house of blues
看看能换多少钱
and see how much we can get for it.
想法不错啊
That's a clutch idea.
嘿 快走开
Hey, get away from there. Go on! Get off it.
你们在干什么
What you all doin'?
快滚
Go on, get outta here!
- 嘿 你们看看 - 滚回家吧
- Hey, you guys, see if... - Go on. Run home to mommy.
看看他们有没有在椅子下落了个包
Hey, see if they left a backpack under my bench.
亚特兰大 紧急呼叫中心
Atlanta 911.
你能听懂吗
Can you understand me?
可以 请讲
Yes. go ahead.
你们无视民兵的命令
You defy the order of the militia.
您说什么
What?
我又接到一个奇怪的电话
I got another weird one.
理查德 包不是他们的
Well, it ain't theirs, Richard.
情况不妙啊
I don't like this.
这个包有点可疑
We got ourselves a suspicious package.
我们最好请求支援
We better call it in.
可能只是有人喝醉 忘在这里了
Probably just somebody run off drunk and forgot they left.
我还是觉得应该请求支援
I still think we ought to call it in.
理查德 拿去失物招领处就好了
Just take it to lost and found, Richard.
我们不应该先打开看看吗
Shouldn't we unzip it, and see what's inside first?
你别碰了
No, no, you don't wanna touch that.
我们得遵守规定
You gotta follow protocol.
真醉了 非落下个包在你凳子底下
Son of a bitch had to get left under your bench, didn't it?
发现丢失包裹 请求援助
We need assistance on an unclaimed bag...
可疑包裹
A suspicious package.
第四区发现可疑包裹
A suspicious package over at section four.
我们应该建起隔离防护
We ought to set up some kind of a perimeter, too.
- 疏散民众 - 隔离
- Just back away. - Perimeter?
理查德 你疯了吗
Richard, you crazy?
我疯了
You know what? I would rather be crazy
也比现在错了好
than wrong right now.
理查德 那肯定就是一包啤酒
Shit, Richard. It's just full of beer.
同志们 楼下有情况
Hey, guys, there's a situation downstairs.
你们得离开
We're gonna have to get you outta here.
什么情况
What kinda situation?
我们在调查
Well, we're lookin' at a suspicious package
塔前边的一个可疑包裹
in front of the tower.
执法部门已经注意到了 正在现场
Law enforcement is aware and they're on the scene.
如果警察让我们走 我们会走的
Well, if the cops tell us we gotta go, we'll go.
乐队正在表演
I mean, the band's in the middle of a set.
我们没法直接关闭
We can't just shut down.
我再回来这儿
Yeah, you know what, if I have to come back here,
你们就不会再犹豫了
There's gonna be no questions and no hesitation.
同志们
Hey, guys.
塔前边很有可能有炸弹
We got a bomb scare in front of the tower.
你们注意一下
You should be aware of that.
首都一直有炸弹威胁
We get bomb threats all the time in DC.
什么都没发生
They're never anything.
你呆着吧 我先走了
Cool for you. I'm outta here.
有什么新闻吗
You got anything?
昨天当地警方发现
Local cop discovered yesterday
他是波兰体操运动员的隔代堂兄弟
he's actually second cousins with a polish gymnast.
有故事可写吗
Is that a story?
毫无灵感
Doesn't get me hard.
我也是
Me, neither.
你看起来不错啊
You look nice.
谢谢
Aw, thanks.
有打火机吗
Do you have a lighter?
你知道我不抽烟
You know I don't smoke.
行吧 我去找打火机 一会回来
All right, I'm gonna go find a lighter. I'll be back.
吸烟有害健康
Those'll kill ya.
人终有一死
Well, gotta die of something.
那也不是今天
Not today.
西尔韦 里面还有十一个人
Silver, still got eleven people inside.
我让他们注意一点了
I made them aware of everything.
我们还没开始疏散
We're not evacuating just yet.
你知道这没什么大事
Listen, you know this is a false alarm.
别紧张
Okay? Calm down.
你们在找那个包裹吗
You gentlemen lookin' for the package?
- 是的 在哪 - 跟我来
- Yeah. What have we got? - Follow me.
这边走 不好意思 让一下
Right down here. Excuse us, Excuse us, comin' through.
抱歉
Excuse me.
亚特兰大 紧急呼叫中心
Atlanta 911.
世纪公园有炸弹
There's a bomb in centennial park.
什么
What?
还有三十分钟
You have 30 minutes.
世纪公园的地址有吗
Do you know the address of centennial park?
让一下
I'm gonna need you to move forward.
不好意思 让一下
Excuse me, folks. excuse me, if you could move in.
你们离开这个凳子
I need you boys to get off the bench.
妈妈 我好累
I'm gettin' tired, mom.
- 同志们 站起来 - 我也好累
- Guys, get up, please. - Yeah, me, too.
女士们 请离开椅子
I need you ladies to move off that bench.
走吧
Come join us.
咱拍张照就走吧
Let's get the last of these pictures and we'll go home.
好
Okay.
往这边走
Move this way.
在这
Right there. Right there.
我不知道这包在那儿多久了
I don't know how long it's been there.
天呐 我们训练的时候听过那句话
Oh, lord. They told us in training.
如果你看到拆炸弹的人脸色苍白 赶紧跑
"you ever see the bomb guy go pale, run."
包里有三个管炸弹
We got three pipe bombs in that bag.
是我见过最大的
Biggest I've ever seen.
我们需要立刻清理出一百英尺的隔离空地
We need to clear a 100-foot perimeter immediately.
你们有拆弹装备吗
Y'all got a bomb blanket?
安全起爆小组能在二十分钟内到达
The render-safe team can be here in 20 minutes.
理查德
Richard...
我再也不会嘲笑你了
I'm never giving you shit about anything ever again.
- 大家动起来 - 往后退
- All right, we need to move! - All right, back up.
大家现在往后退
Everybody back now.
请大家往前走
Everyone, start moving forward, please!
我们需要你们的帮助
Everybody, we need you to help us out.
请离塔远一些
Away from the tower, please.
往前走
Move forward!
我们需要你们帮忙清场出隔离带
Folks, we're gonna need you to help us secure a perimeter.
请你们现在马上往前走
We need you to move forward, please! Right now!
笑一下哦
Smile.
请大家往前走
Please, move forward.
请往前走
Move forward, please!
这边 大家
These people on the end,
请往舞台方向走
Please move forward toward the stage.
快点走
Keep moving.
我眨眼了 再来一张
I blinked. Take another one.
左 右 左 右
Left, right. left, right.
请大家往前走
Move forward, please.
大家都会没事的
Please, please, everyone's fine.
别停
Keep moving.
往回走 别停下 注意脚下
Go back. Keep moving. Watch your step.
现在我们需要您的帮助 别担心
We need your help right now. Do not worry.
走起来 女士 请你往前走
Keep it movin', please. ma'am, keep it moving.
谢谢 走起来 谢谢
Thank you. Keep it moving. Thank you.
- 往这边走 - 注意安全
- This way. Come on. - Nice and safe.
小心那个板凳
Be careful of that bench right there.
嘿 我们得马上离开
Hey! We've gotta go right now!
有炸弹 马上离开
We've got a bomb! Get out right now!
现在马上下楼
Downstairs right now!
大家快走
Keep moving! everybody,
留心脚下 注意安全
Watch where you're stepping, please. Be careful.
借过
Excuse me.
所有人 立刻撤离
Guys, we have got to evacuate!
听到了吗
Hey! Are you listenin' to me?
立刻离开这里 炸弹要爆炸了
We gotta evacuate the tower! We have a bomb! right now!
打扰了 请靠近舞台
A little closer to the stage. Sorry.
所有人离塔远一点
Just come a little further away from the tower.
所有人立刻离开 动起来
Guys, we gotta go right now. Come on.
炸弹就要爆炸了 立刻撤离
We got a bomb! You've gotta go now!
都这个时候了 别再想着看杰克麦克的演出了
You afraid you're gonna miss the Jack Mack concert?
动起来 立刻下楼
Come on! Get down there right now!
炸弹要爆炸了
We got a bomb!
大家立刻离开这里
Come on, guys. We gotta move!
快 快 快
Move, move, move!
再快一点 来不及了
Get the lead outta your pants! Come on now!
塔里的人都撤出来了
Building's all clear.
理查德 你也快点离开这里
You should get outta here, Richard.
- 你也是 - 去吧
- Yeah, you, too. - Go.
所有人 离塔远一点
Guys, move away from the tower! Come on,
- 离塔远一点 - 这片区域都要清空吗
- Move away from the tower! - We have to leave the whole area?
发生了什么
What is happening?
都去街上 总之离开这里
Go toward the street! Anything but here!
都什么时候了你俩还卿卿我我呢
Are you kidding me?
快点离开这里 炸弹就要
We gotta move! There's a bomb...
你们俩没事吧
You two all right?
没事
Yeah, I think so.
妈妈
Mom.
快点 这里
Come on, this way. Let's go.
快起来
Come on, darling.
快走
Let's go.
跑起来
You run out.
天呐
Oh, god.
兄弟 你还好吗
Hey. You all right?
感觉怎么样
How bad?
我很好
I'm fine.
- 我很好 - 好的
- I'm fine. - All right.
兄弟 你会没事的 坚持住
You're gonna be all right, brother.
救护车快到了 不要动
Help's on the way. Don't move.
这里有药和绷带吗
Can we get some medical over here, please?
让他们别靠近那里
Move them back!
可能会有二次爆炸
There could be a second device!
快走 不要停 快走 不要停
Let's go. Keep it movin'! Let's go. Keep it movin'!
快走 不要停
Let's go. Keep it movin'!
立刻
Right now.
有几个人受伤了 我们需要援助
Several people down. We need assistance.
立刻支援
We need it right now!
不要停
Keep moving.
跟着箭头一直走
Follow these arrows. Keep moving.
妈妈
Mom?
A队 这里发生爆炸了
A team, there was an explosion.
请尽快调遣救护车
Send as many ambulances as you have.
坚持住 我需要帮助
Hang on. I'm gonna need help.
有人员伤亡了 我们负责
This is homicide. It's ours.
这个公园是国有的 所以是我们负责
This park is state property. That makes it ours.
你们俩都可以滚了 这是爆炸物管理局的事情
You guys can both get the fuck out of here. this is ATF.
你们都闭嘴吧
Actually, you can all shut the fuck up,
这已经是联邦级别的罪行了
'cause this is a federal crime.
这意味着这件事将由
That means it's our jurisdiction.
联邦调查局全权负责
The federal bureau of investigation.
所以 如果你们想帮忙
So, if you wanna help,
照顾好伤员
get these injured people taken care of.
保证周边安全
And keep the perimeter secure.
帮助我们找出真凶
Help us find out who did this.
妈妈 我想这应该是你的留言机
Hey, mama, I guess I got your message machine.
我是理查德 我在音乐节现场
Uh, it's Richard. I'm down here.
这里刚刚发生了一场爆炸 但我没事
A bomb went off down here, but I'm okay.
我只是想告诉你 等你醒了 打开电视就能看到了
I just called to say when you get up, just turn on the TV.
我爱你
I love you.
上帝啊
Dear god...
不管是谁做的
Whoever did this,
请保佑我们要第一个找到他
please let us find him before anybody else does.
不管他是谁
And please, whoever he is,
请让他付出代价
Let him be fucking interesting.
阿门
Amen.
你是朱维尔吗
Are you Jewell?
我是的 先生
Uh, yes... yes, sir.
我是AT&T公司的媒体公关 蒂姆 巴克尔
I'm Tim Barker, AT&T media relations.
我听说了
Did I hear this right?
是你第一个发现了炸弹 是吧
You're the one who discovered the bomb?
是的 先生
Yes, sir, I did.
你知道吗 你是个英雄
That makes you a hero, you know that?
这只是我的本职工作 先生
I was just doin' my job, sir.
很高兴听到你这么说
That's a nice thing to say, Richard,
但是 现在有大批的媒体
But, uh, we're getting requests
想要对你进行采访
from a lot of people who wanna talk to you.
可以吗
Would that be okay?
诸如美国有线新闻网 凯蒂·柯丽克这类
CNN, Katie Couric, those types.
你的上司已经同意了
Your superior gave the okay.
我只想告诉您
I gotta tell ya,
当时有一群保安帮忙疏散人群
There were a whole bunch of folks clearing people out.
警察和医务人员也功不可没
Police personnel, medics. It wasn't just me.
但是你先发现了炸弹
You're the one who spotted the package.
大家都只想听你说 好吗
You're the one people wanna hear from, okay?
要喝点什么吗
Can we get you something to drink, take care of you?
我想来一杯咖啡
I could use a cup of coffee, if they're
- 如果他们想让我上电视的话 - 完全没问题
- gonna make me speak on TV. - Sure. absolutely.
现在坐在我身边的就是理查德 朱维尔
With us now is Richard Jewell,
他就是那名第一个发现了
The security guard who first spotted
装有炸弹的背包的保安
that knapsack that contained the bomb,
并且在炸弹爆炸之前 尽力疏散人群
And began clearing people away before it exploded.
- 欢迎来到我们的节目 理查德 朱维尔 - 谢谢
- Richard Jewell, welcome. - Thank you.
现在很多人都称你为英雄
A lot of people are calling you a hero.
你感觉如何
Do you feel like one?
女士 我只是觉得
No, ma'am. I feel like, uh...
我只是做了我的本职工作
I was a person that did the job
那是我应该做的
that I was supposed to do.
我只是在正确的时间做了正确的事
I was in the right place at the right time
按照培训教的流程进行了疏导
And used my training in the way I was taught.
真正的英雄应该是
The real heroes are
医护人员和消防人员
The paramedics and the firemen,
以及所有那些不顾自身安危
And all the agents that placed themselves
将那些身中弹片
Between, you know, the bomb and the people
失去行动能力的人
that were refusing to move,
从这场爆炸中救出的人
Because they took most of the shrapnel themselves.
- 干得好 雷达 - 但你仍然是这场爆炸中的英雄
- Good for you, Radar. - You played a big role.
你出现在了正确的地点和时间
You were in the right place at the right time
做了正确的事情
And you did the right thing.
非常感谢
Thank you very much. I really appreciate that.
很高兴你能来到我们节目
Thanks so much for coming in.
感谢您的邀请
Thank you for havin' me. I appreciate it.
好的 稍后我们将从亚特兰大现场带回更多报导
And we'll be back with more from Atlanta right after this.
好孩子
My boy.
仔细找
Find it.
很好 继续
That's it. Find it.
在这 标记
Right here. We got one.
理查德 上电视感觉如何
How'd you feel about that one, Richard?
我觉得很棒
I think it went well.
大家都很友善 让我放松了不少
Everybody was really nice. Made me feel okay about it.
- 你表现得很好 - 干得漂亮 理查德
- Yeah. you were great. - Good job, Richard.
谢谢
Hey, thank you.
对了 我有个问题想问你们
Hey, I had a question for y'all.
昨晚和我在一起的一些保安受伤了
I worked with some guys who got injured last night.
包括格林 西尔韦 米勒
Um...Green, Silver, Miller.
你知道他们现在怎么样了吗
You know if they made it out all right?
放心 所有的警卫人员都没有大碍
Yeah. Word is all the cops are gonna make a full recovery.
好的 谢谢你
That's great. Thank you very much.
应该要谢谢你
Thank you.
理查德 让我为你介绍一下
Richard, there's someone I'd like you to meet.
这是Bernstein&Crane出版社的布伦纳先生
This is Mr. Brenner from Bernstein&Crane.
这家出版社在出版界享有盛名
You know the company, they publish books.
很高兴认识您 先生
Uh, nice to meet you, sir.
很高兴见到你 理查德
Hello, Richard. pleasure to meet you.
我想和你谈谈你的英雄事迹
I would like to talk to you about your story.
你现在有空吗
Are you free?
- 我现在可以吗 - 当然当然
- Am I free? Can I talk to him? - Sure, sure.
好的 那我们去喝杯咖啡l
All right. Let's get a cup of coffee.
也许 我们还能吃点东西
Better yet, let's get somethin' to eat.
反正我对吃东西
Uh, you're not gonna hear a complaint
一直没什么意见
out of me for that.
我们请你吃点好的
Let's get you something good.
不用 不用 我要挂了 我挂了
No, no, no. I gotta go. I gotta go.
理查德
Richard.
我的天啊
Oh, my lord.
你出名了
You're everywhere.
电话一直响个不停
I mean, the phone has just been ringing off the hook.
我想我需要一个秘书
I need a secretary.
是吧 我觉得我也需要一个秘书
Yeah, I think I might need a secretary, too.
刚刚有个从纽约来的先生
Some guy from New York
问我想不想出书
just asked me if I wanna write a book.
你开什么玩笑呢
You don't mean it.
我没有开玩笑
No, I'm not kidding you.
他们的确是这么和我说的
They tell me, apparently...
天呐
Oh, lord.
事实上 他们找来了一些人
Apparently, they got somebody
事先将书中的人物和情节想好
who they think up all the stuff in the book,
然后他们拿着稿子问我问题
They type it out and then they just ask you
是还是不是 正确还是错误 有这件事吗
"yes or no," "true or false," "did it happen?"
回答完之后他们就可以给我酬金
Then they pay you.
我就可以这样赚到钱
You do that for money.
天呐 你现在简直是个巨星
Oh, my god, you're a rock star.
连汤姆·布罗考都在谈论你
Tom Brokaw was even talking about you.
我现在脑子一团乱
I can't even think right now.
没事吧 你从昨晚到现在都没休息过
Are you all right? You've been up for so long.
天呐 昨晚真是太可怕了
Oh, my god, it was so horrible.
妈妈 抱歉 我还没好好抱抱你
Mama, I'm sorry. I didn't even hug you.
- 我知道很可怕 - 我当时就在现场
- It was so awful. - I know, I was there.
天呐
Oh, my god.
幸好你昨晚没去
Be thankful that you weren't there.
你本来会去的
You could have been there.
- 我知道 - 我无法想象你去了会发生什么
- I know. - I couldn't have handled that.
你前两天还在那看肯尼·罗杰斯的演出
You were there two nights ago for Kenny Rogers.
- 你知道你昨晚在现场会发生什么吗 - 我知道
Can you imagine if you were there last night? - I know.
赶快坐下 赶快坐下
Sit down, sit down.
你肯定饿了 我给你弄点吃的
You must be really hungry. I'm gonna give you some food.
我的天哪
Oh, my goodness.
妈妈 我真不知道怎么说
Oh, mama, I'm telling you what, it was...
昨晚真的是一团乱
It was complete chaos, mama.
我昨天差点就请了病假
And to think I could've called in sick.
我昨天的状态应该要请假的
Think about how I was feeling yesterday.
-我知道 - 我差点请了病假
- I know. - I could've called in sick.
我知道
I know.
- 我要是不在后果真是不堪设想 - 天呐
- Then what? - Oh, my lord.
肖
Shaw.
- 我先挂了 - 今天怎么样
- No, I gotta go. - Doing okay?
一点都不好
No.
我眼睁睁地看着炸弹爆炸了
That bomb went off on my watch.
那是我的管辖区域
That's my fucking park.
现场的眼线并不多 我们也有责任
We didn't have enough eyeballs there. That's on us.
当务之急还是抓住那个放炸弹的疯子吧
Let's just catch the son of a bitch, yeah?
没错
Yeah.
我需要你去一趟哈伯沙姆县
I need you to get out to Habersham county.
前副警长那里有一些关于
Background on a former sheriff's deputy
这次爆炸案的犯罪嫌疑人的信息
might have some connection to the bombing.
谁
Who is it?
那个保安
The security guard.
你好啊 理查德
Hey, Richard!
干得漂亮 兄弟
Hey, way to go, man.
我们以你为荣
You made us all real proud.
谢谢
Thank you.
克莱尔博士 很高兴您能信任联邦调查局
Dr. Cleere, we wanna thank you for contacting the FBI
提出你对理查德 朱维尔犯罪行为的指控
regarding your suspicions about Richard Jewell.
我先澄清一下
I wanna be clear,
我没有指控他犯罪
I haven't accused him of anything.
我们明白
We completely understand.
我只是
I just...
他现在家喻户晓
I see the attention he's getting.
这种关注度是他一直以来梦寐以求的
It's the kind of attention he was always seeking here.
但他其实有不为人知的阴暗面
Harassing students, pulling people over on the highway.
骚扰学生 在高速公路上随意拦车
Just crazy behavior.
如果我的直觉没有错
And I decided if my fears were correct,
他其实并不是人人称颂的英雄
If he actually wasn't the hero they're making him out to be,
关于他的恶劣行径我有确凿的证据
and I had information pertinent to the fact
却一直没有公之于众
which I failed to bring to light...
现在贸然公布会有生命危险
It could jeopardize lives.
我们明白了 您选择联系我们是正确的
Well, Dr. Cleere, you did the right thing in calling us.
请放心 我们会继续跟进
We will, rest assured, follow up on this.
您介意我们带走这份文件吗
Do you mind if we take this folder with us?
请便
Please.
我们复印一份之后 会把原件还给您
We'll make a copy and get you the original back.
该死的ACOG为什么重新开放公园
Why is the goddamn ACOG reopening that park?
不然我们哪来这么多破事
We don't have shit!
言归正传 我现在想听更多朱维尔的信息
Okay, I wanna hear more about Jewell.
帕特里克你来说
Patrick?
当我着手调查这个案子的时候
Well, when I look at Jewell...
我联想到了1984年洛杉矶奥林匹克现场的炸弹恐慌
I think about the bomb scare at the L.A. Olympics in '84.
一个警察将炸弹放在巴士上后
A bag left on a bus by the same cop
又假装发现了它
who then discovered it.
今年夏天在爱达荷的一场火灾
And the fires in Idaho this summer,
同样是因一个消防员而起
started by a firefighter
他想自导自演 成为救火英雄
who wanted the credit for putting them out.
现在又来了一个
A profile emerges here.
冒牌英雄
The false hero.
采访里
In interviews,
朱维尔对于爆炸的描述含糊其辞
Jewell's account of the bombing seems vague
谈及受害者的时候还有明显的不适
and he looks uncomfortable discussing the victims.
他还在电视采访中说过
I also found that his mentioning on TV
他想回到执法机关工作
that he wanted to get back into law enforcement a bit
十分可疑
inappropriate.
他的身上还有很多疑点
There's a lot here that's troubling.
探员肖目前掌握到的他的信息
And everything that agent Shaw has learned about him,
和这份文件里所写的几乎一致
syncs up with this profile.
是这样吗 汤姆
You agree with that, Tom?
是的 先生
Yes, sir, I do.
盯紧他
Let's put eyes on him.
- 沃森 - 怎么了
- Watson? - Yeah?
- 沃森 - 有事吗
- Watson? - Yeah.
一号线有你的电话
You have a call on line one.
比尔盖茨又来对我嘘寒问暖了吗
Is it Bill Gates randomly wondering
问我需不需要一百万美元
If I need a million dollars?
那我肯定需要
If so, that's an affirmative.
是理查德 朱维尔
It's Richard Jewell.
哪个理查德 朱维尔 是我知道的那个吗
"Richard Jewell" Richard Jewell?
就是那个 接一号线
"Richard Jewell" Richard Jewell, line one.
- 喂 - 布莱恩特先生 您好
- Hello? - Mr. Bryant.
很抱歉打扰您
Hey, uh, I'm sorry to bother you.
我从查号台找到了你的号码
I just got your number from information.
希望您还记得我
I hope you remember me.
别见外 叫我沃森就好了 你现在可是个国民英雄啊
Radar, you can call me Watson. You're a national hero now.
很高兴你能打来 家里的士力架快吃完了
I'm glad you called. We're running out of snickers.
谢谢您
Thank you, sir.
您最近怎么样 家里还好吗
How are you? How's your family?
我们都很好
We're all fine, yeah.
你现在可是今非昔比了
I see you've moved up from video games.
是的 我无意如此 但我想事实已经这样了
Yep, I didn't mean to, but I guess I did.
干得漂亮 真为你感到高兴
Good job. That's a prideful thing.
我能为你做些什么
What can I do you for?
先生 我打电话来
Oh, sir, I was calling you
因为我想知道
Because I wanted to know,
你出过书吗
Have you ever done a book deal?
怎么
Why?
爆炸之后 有些纽约的朋友
With this whole bomb thing, I got these New York guys
叫我写本书
who are asking me to write a book
我对此一窍不通
and I don't really know anything about that,
所以想打给你试试
so I thought maybe I could call you,
你说不定可以帮我
You might be able to help me.
当然 听起来有点牵强
Sure. sounds a little far-fetched,
不过 合同就是合同 但 我们可以谈谈
But contracts are contracts, but I yeah, I, we could talk.
所以你不是
So, are you not
美国小型企业管理局的了是吧
The U.S. Small Business Admin anymore?
我之前打过电话
'cause I tried there first.
不是了 我跳槽了
No, I moved on.
哇 怎么回事
Oh. How come?
生活所迫
Lifestyle decision.
你电话多少
What's your phone number?
- 我电话是 404 - 404
- My phone number is 404... - 404...
- 194 - 194
- 194... - 194...
- 8188 - 8188
- 8188. - 8188.
好的 你先不要签字啥的
All right, well, you just don't sign anything
等我先看一眼 就从这开始吧
until I see it first. We'll start there.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
好 我不会签的 我先等着
Yeah, I won't put a pen to the page. I'll wait on it.
谢谢你 谢谢你抽空
Hey, and thank you, sir. Thank you for your time.
搞定
You got it.
好 拜拜
All right, bye.
- 保持联系 - 好的 先生
- Stay in touch. - Yes, sir.
- 好 - 拜拜
- Okay. - Bye.
别 别
No, no.
别太高兴
Don't get too excited.
- 不会吧 - 没错
- No. - Yes.
别 炖一下 加辣椒酱
No. Simmer down there. Hot Sauce.
嗨 比尔·米勒
Well, Bill Miller.
见到你真好 好久不见了
It's nice to see you. It's been a while.
很高兴见到你 波比
It's nice to see you, Bobi.
我们的英雄呢
Where's the hero?
他在家呢 进来吧
Oh, he's in here. Come on in.
你觉得是哪种电池
What kind of charge you figure it was?
我不确定他用的什么炸弹
I'm not sure what kinda explosive the guy used.
可能是黑火药 火柴头
It could have been black powder, match heads,
也可能是某种氯酸盐里塞了钉子
Maybe some kinda chlorate packed with nails.
你知道吗 搞笑的是
You know, the funny thing is
那个炸药包就是会炸的 对吧
The package was supposed to blow out, right?
所以那些醉汉撞倒它
So, when those drunks, those kids knocked it over,
救了不少人命
They saved a bunch of lives.
因为它就是会爆炸
Because it was supposed to blow out
造成巨大的人员伤亡
into a crowd for maximum casualties.
但他们打翻了它 它就向上炸开了
But when they knocked it on its back, it blew upward.
大多数火力都冲着天上
Most of the ordnance going up into the sky.
炸了 所以
It blew up, so...
总之 你看到的是
All in all, what you're looking at
某种电池
is some kind of battery
和某种计时装置
And some kind of timing device,
像钟一样
Like a simple clock.
可能就跟我的腕表一样
Maybe a wristwatch like I'm wearing.
取决于这家伙有多高科技
Depends how high-tech the guy got.
有些家伙
Some of these guys,
尤其是退伍军人
especially if they're ex-military,
或者某个大学的奇才
or they're some kind of whiz outta some university,
他们就会组装
They're gonna use a combination
不同的炸弹
of different bomb tactics.
其他人就照着他们的做
Other people are following it like a recipe.
他们可能
They're probably
- 会弄断手指 - 是的
- losing a finger to it. - Yeah.
取决于讨论的是谁
But depends on who you're talking about
还有谁做的炸弹
And who's making the bomb.
我想听听你的意见
I like getting your opinion on it,
你肯定做了很多研究
And I'm sure you've studied it quite a bit.
谁知道呢
Who knows?
还是关于炸弹袭击者
That's the thing, too, about these bombers.
你我也可能会
It could have been you or me.
他们有些人 看起来就是普通人
These guys, some of them, look like regular people.
大多数都是
Lot of them do.
是啊
Yeah.
你们压力肯定很大
Must be a lot of pressure on you guys.
平时也差不多
No more so than usual.
确实 只是又一个 谢谢
Sure, just another... thank you.
就是奥运会期间
Just your average deadly bombing
美国大地上的寻常致命轰炸
On U.S. soil during the Olympics.
没什么大不了
No big deal.
不知道诶 你们应该也感受到这种狂热
I don't know, you guys must be feeling the heat, too, huh?
有线电视新闻网铺天盖地报道这事
CNN is going wall-to-wall with this.
他们就是干这个的
Is that why we get this outfit?
那给我爆点料吧
So, then give me something I can print.
凯西 你知道我不能这么做
Kathy, you know I can't do that.
没事 我已经打听到
That's all right. I already know
局子在调查某个人
The bureau's looking into somebody.
你怎么知道
Yeah, what makes you think that?
听朋友说的
Friends.
- 朋友 - 线人
- Friends? - Sources.
线人
Sources?
在调查谁
Who is it?
凯西 要是他们都不告诉你
Well, Kathy, if you couldn't fuck it out of them,
你为什么觉得我会告诉你
What makes you think you're gonna fuck it outta me?
凯西 你知道我烦什么吗
You know what bothers me, Kathy,
是别人不理解要花多少工夫
Is that people don't understand how much work
才能破一个这样的案子
It costs in making a case like this.
它需要日日夜夜拼命
It's effort 24/7.
你说的对
You're right.
不如你教教我
Why don't you educate me?
这次我不能搞砸了
I will not have this screwed up.
那是一场屠杀
That was a massacre out there.
没有更多人受伤是个奇迹
It's a miracle more people weren't killed.
没有第三方线人证实
I would never go to print without
我是不会报道的
independent corroboration from a second source.
我们的关系也会变得很不一样
And that would put us in a very different zone.
你知道的
As you know.
真的吗
Really?
哪种关系
What kind of zone?
等你去发现
You have to find out.
我们在查保安 朱维尔
We're looking at the security guard, Jewell.
- 不是吧 - 没错
- No shit? - No shit.
你会盯着发现炸弹的人
You always look at the guy who found the bomb just like
就像你会盯着发现尸体的人
You always look at the guy who found the body.
但这个人他有前科
But this guy, he's got a bad past.
符合炸弹袭击者T的侧写
Fits the profile of the hero-bomber to me, T
那个和妈妈住一起的肥仔 当然
That fat fuck who lives with his mother. Of course.
我怎么漏了这个 我是说 这太不可思议了
How did I miss that? I mean, that is amazing.
你真行
You are good.
你很棒
You're very good.
是
Yeah.
不过得抓紧时间了
This kind of puts a clock on things though.
你想开房还是就在我车里
You wanna get a room or just go to my car?
终于
This is happening.
是啊
我们走吧
Let's get the fuck outta here.
- 好 - 好
- Okay. - Yeah.
宝贝 我需要你
Sugar, I need you to do
润色一个东西
One of those better word things you do.
你是说帮你改写吗
You mean rewrite you?
是啊 你知道我写得跟屎一样
Yeah, you know I write like a brick,
但这个有点特别
And this one is kinda special.
这是什么
What is it?
没什么 就是
Oh, nothing. It's just that the
联邦调查局在查理查德 朱维尔
The FBI is looking at Richard Jewell
是不是炸弹袭击者
as the bomber.
你现在有空吗
Do you have time for me now?
多久都可以
Oh, I got all the time you need.
- 好 我们干活吧 - 全告诉我
- All right, let's work. - Tell me everything.
你去哪
Where you goin'?
去拿笔记
To get my notes.
最先通知警察有炸弹的保安
The security guard who first alerted police to the pipe bomb
是联邦调查局的调查对象
That exploded in Centennial Olympic Park
那个炸弹在世纪奥林匹克公园爆炸了
Is the target of the Federal Investigation into the incident
导致二人死亡
That resulted in two deaths
数百人受伤
And injured more than one hundred.
理查德 朱维尔 33岁
Richard Jewell, 33,
前执法人员
A former law enforcement officer,
符合独身炸弹袭击者的侧写
fits the profile of the lone bomber.
这份侧写指向
This profile generally includes
一名失意白人 前警官
A frustrated white man who is a former police officer,
军人 或者想当警察的人
Member of the military, or police wannabe
他想当英雄
who seeks to become a hero.
爆炸案发生后朱维尔随之成了英雄
Jewell has become a celebrity in the wake of the bombing,
今天还上节目了
Making appearances on the today show.
- 而且 - 联邦调查局知道你得到了这个消息吗
- Also - The FBI knows you have this?
我的线人说大家都得到消息了
Yeah, my guy says everybody's got it.
网上都有
Networks have it.
有线电视新闻网也有
CNN has it.
有个佐治亚州调查局的人也是这么说的（亚特兰大在在佐治亚州）
Got a guy at GBI says the same thing.
局子在查朱维尔
Bureau's looking at Jewell.
那为什么没人报道
Then why isn't anyone reporting it?
有人觉得我们被下套了吗
Anybody feel like we're getting worked here?
该死的 约翰 这是我们的奥运会
God damn, John, these are our Olympics.
要是我们不带头报道
If we don't lead on this story,
我们他妈的在这干嘛
What the fuck are we doing here?
好吧
Okay.
撕了午间版 换个头版
Tear up the afternoon edition, and replace the front page.
就这么干吧
We're running it.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是有线电视新闻网突发新闻
This is CNN breaking news.
我们被要求逐字逐句
We've been asked to relay the story
转播这则新闻
to you verbatim, which we'll do.
援引自亚特兰大报
"the security guard," and this is a quote from the Atlanta Journal,
最先通知警察有炸弹的保安
"who first alerted police to the pipe bomb
日前在接受联邦调查局调查
That exploded in Centennial Olympic Park,
这个炸弹在世纪奥林匹克公园爆炸
Is the focus of the federal investigation..."
现在 简要回顾下 我们刚得知一些细节
Now, to recap quickly, we are just getting details
看上去是很大的突破
On what appears to be a major development...
祝贺你
Congratulations.
谁他妈泄露给亚特兰大宪报的
Who the fuck leaked this investigation to the AJC?
肖
Shaw!
- 什么事 - 把朱维尔带过来
- Sir? - Get Jewell in here.
非对抗性采访 马上
Non-confrontational interview, today!
- 你好 - 是理查德 朱维尔吗
- Hello? - Richard Jewell?
是的 我是理查德
Yeah. I'm Richard.
联邦调查局特工 丹·班纳特 汤姆 肖
Special agents Dan Bennet, Tom Shaw, FBI.
有时间吗
You got a minute?
有的 进来吧
Yeah, I got a minute. Come on in.
谢谢
Thank you.
您好
Ma'am.
妈妈 这是特工班纳特和肖
Mama, this is agent Bennet and Shaw.
这是我妈妈 波比
This is my mother, Bobi.
- 您好 - 很荣幸 太太
- How do you do? - Pleasure, ma'am.
有什么能帮你们的吗
What can I do for y'all?
其实局子里在做一段
Well, the bureau's actually putting together a training video
关于怎么处理可疑包裹的培训视频
on how to deal with suspicious packages,
我们想让你参加
And we'd love you to be a part of it.
怎么样
How's that sound to you?
我很乐意帮这个忙
I would love to help out with that,
没问题
Yeah, absolutely.
你做到了 理查德
You did it, Richard.
你向他们证明了你可以是个好警察
You showed them what kinda cop you can be.
看看
Look at this.
问题就是我们准备今天拍
See, the only thing is that we're shooting it today.
所以 我们需要你
So, we'd need you to
跟我们去一趟分局
To follow us to the field office right now.
因为时间有点紧 可以吗
Because time's a little bit tight. Is that okay?
你知道吗 我很乐意
You know what? I would love to,
但我今天还得工作
But I still gotta work today.
该我轮班了
I got my shift.
要不了多久的 理查德
Ah, this won't take long, Richard.
好吧 这样吧
Yeah, you know what? um...
我觉得可以的
I bet we can make that work.
我可以打电话告诉他们
I can call in and tell 'em
我迟点到
I'm gonna be a little bit late.
我是说 我想帮你们 我也是执法人员
I mean, I wanna help you all, and I'm law enforcement, too.
我们知道 没错
We know that. Yes, indeed.
是的
Yeah.
好吧 那准备好走了吗
All right. So, you're all set to go then, huh?
好
Great.
- 走吧 - 很高兴见到你 太太
- Let's do it. - Lovely to meet you, ma'am.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
- 很高兴见到你 - 家里很漂亮
- Nice to meet you. - Lovely home.
我不知道这是怎么了
I don't know what's going on.
我为你感到自豪
I'm so proud of you.
天呐
Oh, goodness.
朱维尔先生 联邦调查局的人怎么来了
Mr. Jewell, why are the FBI here?
朱维尔先生 他们说了什么
Mr. Jewell, what have they told you?
他们让你重返岗位吗
Are they letting you go back to work?
是啊
Uh, yeah.
他们让你去工作吗 你可以出来吗
They're letting you go to work? You're good to go?
没错
Yeah.
联邦调查局在查你吗
Are the FBI investigating you?
我猜任何那天晚上在公园的人
Uh, I imagine they'll investigate anyone
他们都会调查吧
Who was at the park that night.
也包括你们
That includes all of you, too.
他们有说你不能出城吗
Have they told you yet you can't leave town?
没
No.
- 朱维尔先生 你被捕了吗 - 你是自由身吗
- Mr. Jewell, are you under arrest? - You're free to go wherever you like?
你是自由身吗
You're free to go wherever you like?
理查德 你是自由身吗
You're free to go wherever you'd like, Richard?
- 谁是你同伙 - 那边怎么回事
- Who are you working with? - What happened out there?
大家在说
What do you think of the appearance
你是头号嫌犯 你怎么看
that people are saying that you are now the prime suspect?
理查德 怎么回事
What's going on, Richard?
- 理查德 - 我不是嫌犯
- Richard - I'm not a suspect.
为什么联邦调查局要找你谈话
Why are you talking to the FBI?
朱维尔先生 为什么联邦调查局要找你
Mr. Jewell, what does the FBI want with you?
可以透露一下吗
Can you give us any more information?
不好意思 我感觉有记者跟着我
Sorry, I think I got some media following me.
不 那是我们的人 伙计
No. Those are our guys, bud. Those are our guys.
理查德 朱维尔 33岁
"Richard Jewell, 33,
前执法部门职工
A former law enforcement officer,
据说
The story goes on to say,
符合独身炸弹袭击者的侧写
"fits the profile of the lone bomber.
这份侧写指向
This profile generally includes
一名失意白人 前警官
A frustrated white man who is a former police officer,
军人 或想当警察的人
member of the military, or police wannabe
他想当一个英雄
who seeks to become a hero.
保安最先通知警察有炸弹
The security guard who first alerted police to the pipe bomb...
炸弹随后在世纪奥林匹克公园爆炸
That exploded in Centennial Olympic Park."
那直到情况不对劲为止
So, up until it obviously went sideways,
一切正常 是吗
Everything pretty normal about that evening, right?
是的 再寻常不过了
No, it was a regular night from what I could tell.
大伙玩得很开心
Everyone was having a great time.
像是场狂欢
It was like a celebration.
对 没有一丝
Yeah. no air of...
你玩得正尽兴
Yeah, you were having fun.
我很开心 很享受
I was having fun. It was a good time.
但那有几个人
But there was, uh, some guys
扔些瓶子或者类似的 对吗
with beer cans or something like that?
就在塔后面
Guys behind the tower.
他们在干什么 在扔
What were they doing there? They were throwing...
啤酒瓶 - 哦对 啤酒瓶
- beer bottles. - beer bottles. yeah.
他们大吵大闹
They were horsing around, fooling.
我打断他们并对此劝阻
I broke it up and I gave 'em a talking-to,
然后他们走了
And they left. Yep.
这还是在塔后面吧
And that was behind the tower?
对 长官 - 好
- Yes, sir. - Right.
接着你绕着塔转了转
So then you came back around the tower
在那你发现了可疑背包
And that's where you saw the package unattended?
对 - 嗯好
- Yes, sir. - Right.
那你发现有人正从凳子那走开吗
And did you see anyone walking away from the bench?
不 长官 要是发现我会跟上去的
No, sir. I would've tailed them if I did.
好
Yeah.
那就是说你不知道是谁弄的炸弹
So, you have no idea who might have put that package there?
对 长官
No, sir.
无论罪犯是谁 都逃不过审判
But whoever did, I think they ought to fry.
对 我们也同意 理查德
Oh. yeah. We think so, too, Richard.
必然如此
Absolutely.
这样 我们接下来呢
So, here's what we're gonna do.
要尽量严肃正经
We're trying to be as authentic as possible
所以这要求我们得像审犯人一样
And part of that has to do with how you treat a suspect.
好吗 所以我们要
All right? So, what we're gonna do is
要假装
We're gonna pretend
你就是犯罪嫌疑人
that we actually brought you in, in that regard.
好吗 - 这
- Right? - That...
我们会宣读你的米兰达权利
And we read you your Miranda rights
然后你要选择放弃
And you've agreed to waive them.
哦对了 你还得填个表
In fact, we have a form you can sign.
对 为什么你不
Yeah. why don't you...?
就这个
This'll be good.
看起来更正式点
Just so it looks real.
嗯 你就在那签个字
Yeah. so, you just sign the bottom there
我们把它录上
And we'll get that on tape
然后我们继续采访
And then we'll continue on with the interview.
好
Okay.
嗯
Yeah.
不好意思 理查德 可能我没说明白
I'm sorry, Richard, maybe I wasn't clear.
你得在上面签字 不是比划一下
You actually have to physically sign the paper.
这可是个有法律效益的文件 - 噢
- This is a real document. - Well...
对呀 我们不是要正式嘛 理查德
Of course. we're going for authenticity here, Richard.
这样看起来才会真呀
It has to be real for the video.
不好意思 长官 我不
I'm sorry, sir. I don't...
我不认为我愿意
I don't think I would feel comfortable
签这种东西
signing something like this.
理查德 我们只想
Richard, we just want...
这样吧 我们稍作休息
You know what? Why don't we take a quick break?
停一下录像 - 好
- Go ahead and stop the camera. - Okay.
嗯
Um...
嗯好 - 我俩商量个事
- Yeah. okay. - We'll just talk for a second.
马上就来 - 很快
- We'll be right back. - Right back.
我以前是个副警长
I was a sheriff deputy.
在哈伯沙姆县干的
Habersham county.
好了 理查德
All right, Richard,
我们就当这一切都没发生过
We're gonna pretend like none of that ever happened.
重新开始 好吗
Let's get a new tape going. okay?
嗯
Uh...
接下来呢
What we're gonna do now...
我拿着呢
There you go. I got it.
扔掉了
Get her out there and we'll throw it away.
接下来呢
What we're gonna do now is
班纳特特工会进来
Agent Bennet's gonna come back in the room,
他重新介绍下自己
He's gonna reintroduce himself,
像正式采访一样向你出示证件
Show you his credentials just like a professional interview
紧接着
And then we're gonna
我们会宣读你的米兰达权利
Actually read you your Miranda rights.
为什么读这个
Why would he do that?
为了更显正式呀 理查德
Well, to make it more authentic, Richard.
越正式越好
We want this to look as authentic as possible.
进来吧 特工班纳特
Come on in, agent bennet.
朱维尔先生
Mr. Jewell...
特工丹 班纳特 你有权保持
Special agent Dan Bennet, FBI. You have the right to...
不好意思 我觉得
I'm sorry. I think... I'm sorry.
我有必要联系我的律师
I think maybe I should contact my attorney.
为什么突然要联系他呢 理查德
Now, why would you wanna do that, Richard?
我是说
I mean...
你不是英雄吗
You're the hero, right?
你不会隐瞒些什么事情吧
Unless there's something you wanna tell us.
没有 只不过
No. but I just...
我觉得最好还是联系一下
think I better call him.
好吧
Okay.
给你
Here you go.
9号键
Press nine.
对 请帮我转接
Yes, hello, I'm calling information to get ahold...
沃森 布莱恩特 一个律师
The name is Watson Bryant. he's a lawyer.
谢谢 请保持联系
Thank you. Yeah, connect me.
他不在线
I'm getting his message machine.
所以我给他留个言
So, I'm gonna leave a message for him.
嗯好 留言吧
Go ahead. leave a message and that'll be...
我是沃森
This... this is Watson.
沃森 布莱恩特 我是理查德 朱维尔
Watson Bryant, this is Richard Jewell
打给你是因为
Calling in regards to, um,
有些急事
Something somewhat serious.
希望能回电
I would like you to call me back.
我在亚特兰大的FBI办公室
I'm at the FBI office in Atlanta.
尽早回电
If you could call me back at your earliest convenience.
不胜感激
Thank you. bye.
你怎么不带电话呢
You can't leave your phone off.
我得联系你呀
I have to be able to reach you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
又想买粉底了
You need more toner?
他给你打了三次电话 - 谁打了
- He called three times. - Who? Who called?
谁 - 理查德啊
Who? Richard.
都是从FBI问询室给你打来的
Three times from the FBI interrogation room.
知道了知道了 先别急
All right, all right, all right, slow down.
我的天
Jesus christ.
他只认识我这一个律师吗
Am I the only lawyer this guy knows?
对
Yes.
报纸上说
The paper says...
政府已经控制住他了
Paper says the bureau has him dead to rights.
我的家乡常说
Where I come from,
政府宣判一个人有罪
when the government says someone's guilty,
那此人必定清白
it's how you know they're innocent.
这里不同吗
It's different here?
我不知道 情况有点糟
I don't know. Looks pretty bad.
我不管
I don't care.
我们明天会有三四个像这样的案子
We'll get three or four cases as juicy as this tomorrow,
你还有这么多的事没做
And you have so much else to do.
知道了知道了
All right, all right, all right.
帮我打给办公室 娜德雅
Connect me with the field office, would you, Nadya?
马上
Right away.
谢谢
Thank you.
你要是不忙的话
Unless you're too busy.
你不忙吗
Don't you have any work to do?
我暂时没别的事
I have nothing else to do, no.
你好 我是沃森 布莱恩特 理查德 朱维尔的律师
Yes, this is Watson Bryant, attorney for Richard Jewell.
我想和我的委托人说几句话
I'd like to speak to my client, please.
不好意思先生
I'm sorry, sir,
这里没有此人
But we have no one here by that name.
不 你们有
Yeah, you do, actually.
给我把电话给他 就现在
Put me on the phone with my client now.
请稍后回电 先生
Please call back later, sir.
到时我们可能有最新消息
Maybe we'll have more information.
帮我重拨一下 好吗
Dial that number again, would you?
喂 又是我
Yeah, this is Watson Bryant again,
理查德的律师
Attorney for Richard Jewell.
我下通电话会打给《60分钟》节目的迈克 华莱士
My next call is gonna be to mike wallace of 60 minutes
问问为什么FBI在合法审讯时
To ask him why the FBI would deny a citizen
会忽视宪法赋予的公民权利
his constitutional right to legal counsel.
能告诉我你的名字吗
Can I have the spelling of your name, please?
有人找你
Got a call for you.
你好
Hello?
理查德 我是沃森 你在那干什么
Richard, it's Watson. What are you doing in there?
他们说有个培训短片需要我帮忙
They said they needed me for a training film.
不 他们骗你的
No, they don't need you for...
你现在是犯罪嫌疑人了
You're a suspect.
你看报纸了吗
Have you read the newspapers?
你有没有签署什么文件
Have you signed anything?
那你承认什么东西了吗
Have you confessed to anything?
不 当然没有 我不是罪犯
No, of course not. I didn't do this.
好的 听我说 竖起耳朵仔细听
All right, listen to me. listen to me real carefully.
保持沉默 什么也别说
Just don't say anything to anyone.
听明白没
You understand me?
赶紧离开
Get your ass outta there.
把电话给主管
Let me talk to the agent in charge.
他想跟你说话
He wants to talk to you.
我是特工 肖
This is agent shaw.
问询到此结束
This interrogation's over.
别再多问了 明白没
Not another word, you hear me?
他一直很配合的
He's been cooperating fully.
你耳背吗
Hey, did I stutter?
到此结束
No more questions!
把他送走 懂了没
Get his ass outta there, you hear me?
好吧 祝你
Okay. well, have a nice...
给我挂了
He hung up on me.
你的律师嗓门真大 恭喜了
You have a very loud lawyer. Congratulations.
你被指控了吗
Were you charged?
是你安放的炸弹吗
Did you do it? Did you set that bomb?
理查德 FBI都跟你说什么了
Richard, what did the FBI say to you?
他们说了什么
Richard, what did they say?
FBI跟你说什么了 理查德
What did the FBI say to you, Richard?
FBI指控你了吗
Did the FBI charge you?
是你放的炸弹吗
Did you set that bomb, Richard?
能告诉我们一些采访有关的事情吗
What can you tell us about the FBI interview?
理查德 FBI说了什么 告诉我们
Richard, what did the FBI say to you? Just tell us.
我们现在
We're having some trouble
联系不上布莱恩 斯科特
Connecting to Blaine Scott.
希望一会有最新进展
We hope to have more from him later.
它可以告诉我们一些交通状况
He can tell us about the traffic situation,
并且由于世纪公园
Also since centennial park is...
他们现在盯上我了
They're all after me now.
他也许是唯一一个突破点
He may be our only view of the park for a while.
我们会核实的
We'll be checking back.
现在 我们把画面交给
Right now we're gonna throw it back to...
全国广播公司和汤姆 布罗考
NBC news and Tom Brokaw.
普遍推测
The speculation is that the FBI
按FBI的话说 他们已经要立案侦查了
is close to "making the case," in their language.
可能已经有足以逮捕他的证据了
They probably have enough to arrest him right now,
也可能足以起诉他了
Probably enough to prosecute him,
但也要有足够证据来给他定罪
but you always wanna have enough to convict him as well.
案件目前仍有疑点
There are still some holes in this case.
为什么汤姆 布罗考这么说你
Why did Tom Brokaw say that about you?
这是汤姆 布罗考
That was Tom Brokaw
关于世纪公园爆炸案的最新谈话
with the latest update on the centennial park bombing.
当我们再次回来
When we come back...
我不知道
I don't know.
嘿 这是谁 - 不知道
- Hey, who's this? - I don't know.
没见过他
I don't know who this guy is.
跟我来 跟上他 跟他上
Come with me. Let's get him, Let's get him.
先生先生 你是谁
Sir? sir? sir? Who are you, sir?
你是理查德的朋友吗
Are you Richard's friend?
你来这里要见谁吗
Who are you here to see?
你是理查德的朋友吗
Are you a friend of Richard's?
你来这里做什么 - 你是谁
- Why are you here? - Who are you?
我是他的朋友
I'm a friend of Richard's.
能给我们一些内部消息吗
Can you give us some insight?
是你帮他安置炸弹的吗
Did you help him set that bomb?
你叫什么名字 请告诉我们
What's your name? Tell us anything at all.
你是他家庭一员吗
Are you a family member?
我是他的朋友
I'm a friend of Richard's.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 - 外面一团糟
- Hey. - Shit show out there.
你现在还有欠我的那一百美元吗
You got that $100 you owe me?
噢 你一定是他妈妈
Oh, you must be mom.
身体还好吗 我是沃森
How are you? I'm Watson.
很抱歉这个世界跟疯了一样
I'm so sorry the world has gone insane.
啊 太吵了
Ah, that's annoying.
关了它吧 好吗
Let's get rid of that, shall we? Uh...
有点像电钻在耳朵里嗡嗡
It's kind of like a drill in your ear.
接下来一段时间
For the next little while,
你只能跟我说话
The only person you need to talk to is me.
要是来了警察
He does not open his mouth again
FBI探员 或者佐治亚州调查局还有别的什么人
If there's a cop present,
他也不能开口
Or an FBI agent, or someone from GBI, or a crossing guard.
够清楚了吗
Is that clear?
我生来被教育要尊重权威 先生
I was raised to respect authority, sir.
小子 所谓权威就是
Son, authority's what's outside that window
现在在窗外面想生吞你的那帮人
looking to eat you alive.
来杯啤酒吧
How about a beer?
嗯
Oh...
嗯好 我给你拿吧
Yeah. yeah, sorry. Let me grab you something.
不不 谢谢你了
No, no. thanks, radar.
没事
Yeah.
我得和你儿子独处一段时间
I'm gonna need to be alone with your son.
虽然我不想太无礼
I hate to be rude,
但如果有第三者在的话 那谈话就失效了
But if there's a third party, there's no privilege.
噢好
Oh.
嗯 第三者 他们可以强迫我们
Yeah, third party, then they can
说任何事情
compel anything we say.
嗯好
No.
很高兴见到你
Very nice to meet you.
抱歉刚刚的无礼 波比 谢谢配合
Sorry to be rude, Bobi. thanks.
你参加过什么极端组织吗 理查德
You belong to any extremist groups, Richard?
没有 我讨厌那些东西
No, I hate all that stuff.
那反政府机构呢
Any anti-government affiliations or...?
也没有
No.
你有什么朋友
Any of your friends affiliated
参加过
with any sort of that organization?
不不 我不觉得有
No, no, I do not believe so.
宗教狂热团体呢
Religious cults?
没有 除非浸信会（基督教新教教派）也算
Not unless being a baptist is a religious cult.
全国步枪协会呢
NRA?
NRA也算极端组织吗
Is the NRA a fringe group?
那你有和3K党人待在一起过吗
You ever hung out with any ku klux klan members?
即便我有 也不是有意的
If I did, it wouldn't have been on purpose.
你联系过任何其他律师吗
You contacted any other lawyers about this book deal?
没有 你是唯一一个 - 嗯
- No. you're the only one. - Mmm-hmm.
理查德 这是重罪
Richard, this is a capital crime here.
够判死刑的
This is the death penalty.
只有我知道真相 我才能帮你
I can help you, but only if I know the truth.
是你放的炸弹吗
Did you do this?
当然不
No.
你刚刚是怀疑我吗
Are you asking if I did it?
我是在询问你
I'm asking you if you had any part
你参加过世纪公园的爆炸行动吗
of the centennial bombing, yes.
所以 你要是有任何
So, if you had anything to do with this,
参加过任何部分
had any part in this...
我没有
I didn't...
我没有放炸弹
I did not plant that bomb in centennial park
而且我以为你知道这个 是我错了
And I made the mistake of assuming you knew that.
好吧 那
All right, well, let's beat
让我们一起打败那些垃圾们吧
The hell out of these bastards.
好吗
Okay?
你是他的律师吗
Are you his attorney?
你和理查德 朱维尔的关系是什么
What is your relationship with Richard Jewell?
要是FBI不调查他的话
I think the FBI would be derelict
这会是FBI的失职的
not to investigate Richard Jewell.
他们只是完成自己的工作而已
They're just doing their jobs.
你什么时候会再和他见面
When are you meeting with him again?
不 他们职责所在而已
No, they're just doing their job.
为了确保万无一失
They're just making sure no rock is unturned.
你一会还是和他见面吗
Are you gonna meet with him again soon?
不好意思
Excuse me.
是的 我和理查德已经是十年老友了
Yes. I've been friends with Richard for 10 years.
你是他的律师吗 - 对
- Are you his lawyer? - I am.
是他安的炸弹吗
Did he set that bomb?
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
你会为他辩护吗
You'll be defending him?
有可能
Possibly.
不是真正的法律身份吧 布莱恩特先生
Not quite real estate law, is it, Mr. Bryant?
哇哦 我的天
Whoa! Jesus Christ!
你他妈的是谁
Who the hell are you?
我会是你最好的战友
I could be the best friend you'll ever have.
凯西 斯克鲁格斯 是亚特兰大宪报的
Kathy Scruggs. AJC.
你说是就是
Of course you are.
听着 - 下车
- Listen... - Get out.
你真的为理查德朱维尔
Have you secured an actual
做辩护律师了吗
defense attorney for Richard yet?
无可奉告
No comment.
赶紧下车
Get out of the car.
你看啊 无可奉告是不能帮你的
See, "no comment" doesn't help me,
也就是说我帮不了你
which means I can't help you.
这就是你想做的吗 你想帮我吗
Is that what you wanna do? You wanna help me?
沃森 我看你可能
Watson, I don't get the sense you
没有注意到你现在的危险处境
grasp the tank that's about to roll over you.
我们说的可是美国政府
We're talking about the U.S. government here
他们在调查恐怖袭击案
investigating a terrorism act.
你需要我
You need me.
听着 疯丫头 你想让我叫警察吗
Okay, listen, crazy lady, you want me to call the cops?
噢那可真是太好了
Oh, please do.
警察喜欢我的 我经常给他们讲故事
The cops love me. I tell their stories all day.
不如说说你的吧
Let me tell yours.
我只会问
I'm just gonna ask
几个能帮叙述你故事的小问题
A couple questions that'll help you tell your story.
并且你需要我来 - 赶紧下车
- And you need me to help... - Get out. Get out of my...
你是真的有种 - 那可不
- You got some balls, man. - Yes, I do.
滚出去
Get out.
别啊 就只问几个小问题
Come on. I'll just ask you a few questions.
滚吧 - 我们可以一起下车的
- Get out. - We can go together.
来吧 我带了笔记本的
Come on. I'll get my notepad.
给老子快他妈的下车
Get the fuck out of my car now!
从车里滚出去
Get out of my car!
我受够了
I'm sick of this shit.
你知道从哪找我
You know where to find me.
别担心 - 我从来没上过电视还
- Yeah. Don't worry. - Never been on TV before.
没事的
You'll be fine.
朱维尔的律师 布莱恩特先生
Mr. Jewell's attorney, Mr. Bryant.
感谢到访 - 不客气
- Thanks for coming in. - You're welcome.
关于调查你的委托人这件事
What are the authorities telling you
当局有跟你说些什么吗
about their suspicions about your client?
没有
Uh, nothing.
什么也没有吗
No communication whatsoever?
他们只告诉我
Uh, all they've said to me is that
不会逮捕他而已
They're not going to arrest him.
这是他们昨天说的原话
That's what they told me yesterday.
你信吗
You believe that?
显然不
No.
那你就是觉得他会被逮捕
You think they are going to arrest him?
我觉得他们不会告诉我
I don't think they'd tell me
是否会逮捕他 就这样
Whether they were or they weren't. That's all.
你认为FBI在调查过程中
What do you think of the manner
对待你的委托人的方式
In which the FBI has treated your client
是否不妥 - 我认为那个
- pursuing this investigation? - I think whoever the bum was
将理查德朱维尔引上
that leaked that Richard Jewell
风口浪尖的坏蛋
Was the focus of this investigation,
他才应当被起诉
He deserves to be prosecuted
或者用别的方法来惩罚
or dealt with in some serious way.
我不认为调查过程
I don't think that this investigation
应该曝光在世界关注之下
should be conducted under world spotlight,
如果你愿意像目前一样
If you will, like this.
关于今天被搜查的小屋一事
What's your client told you about this cabin
你的委托人如何告知你的
that's being searched today?
据我所知那是他以前的住所
It's his former residence, as I understand it.
有些事你得明白
You need to understand something.
自从前天晚上
I have barely had the time to take a breath in this case
我几乎没有休息时间
since it started the other night.
我们得应对媒体 FBI
We have been reacting to the media, to the FBI,
我甚至没有准备好
and I have not sat down
这次深入访谈中
and conducted an in-depth interview
你们问我的相关问题
about all these things that y'all are asking me about.
那你为什么如此确信他是无辜的呢
Then why are you so convinced of his innocence?
因为我认识他有段时日了
Because I've known Richard for a while.
我还看他的眼睛问他是否是罪魁祸首
I've looked him in the eye and I've asked him the question.
但是你得承认
But you've admitted to me,
你甚至都不知道他还有个小屋
You didn't even know he had a cabin.
你也不了解他先前的逮捕
You didn't know about this prior arrest.
也不知晓他先前的劣习
You didn't know about the prior misdemeanors.
他有很多你不知道的事
There's a whole lot of priors you didn't know about.
我没有完整了解过
I have not conducted a thorough investigation
理查德的过去 - 当然 这我明白
- into Richard's history. - No, I understand all that.
我想我问的是
I guess what I'm asking you is
既然你没有调查过他
considering that you haven't done that,
他又有很多你不知道的事情
and considering there are things that you didn't know,
为什么你还觉得他是清白的呢
why are you so convinced of his innocence?
因为我相信他
Because I believe him.
就这么简明扼要吗
Plain and simple?
对 没错
Yeah. that's right.
有很多人
I don't know a whole lot of things
关于他们我也不了解呀
About a whole lot of people that I know.
我没有理查德的在警记录
I don't have Richard's police records. You may. I don't...
我也不急着完成什么指标 这就是全部了
I have not gotten up to speed on some things. That's all.
但我不知道这些事情
But just because I don't know these things
并不意味着
doesn't mean that I don't have a feel
我不能从理查德的角度出发来思考
for where I think Richard is in this case.
那你知道哈伯沙姆警局
Were you aware that the habersham sheriff's department
曾要求他去做心理咨询吗
had asked him to seek psychological counseling?
这我也不清楚
I don't know that either.
但是我知道许多人
But I know a lot of people
都得去做心理咨询
who ought to have psychological counseling.
沃森 布莱恩特 感谢您的到来
Watson Bryant, I thank you very much.
谢谢 再见
See ya. Thank you.
22小时后 我们马上回来
Twenty-two past the hour. we'll be right back.
首先
First of all,
我们要向公众保证
We wanna reassure the public that
尽管昨日发生了如此惨剧
Atlanta is a safe place...
但是亚特兰大依旧是一个安全的地方
In spite of the tragedy of last evening.
喂
Hello?
你曾因为冒充警察
Were you arrested
而被逮捕过吗
for impersonating an officer?
是啊有过一次
Yeah, once.
- 当时情况很复杂 - 当时
- It was complicated. - It was...
你有打算告诉我吗
Were you planning on telling me?
当然了我只是
Yeah, of course. I just...
昨天吹上天了给忘了
In all the hoopla yesterday, I guess I just forgot.
我的老天爷啊
Jesus Christ! What the...
还有什么东西你忘记了吗
Was there anything else that you forgot?
因为刚刚我在今日节目里面
'Cause I just had my ass handed to me
可倒了大霉了
On the fucking today show!
谢谢您嘞
Thanks a lot.
真是好消息呢
More great news.
这要成为王者的男人
The man who would be king,
迈克尔 约翰逊 来自得克萨斯州韦科市
Michael Johnson, Waco, Texas,
正在试着完成在奥林匹克场上
Attempting to do what no man
前无古人的伟大壮举
Has ever done in Olympic competition,
同时赢得400米和200米短跑冠军
Win both the 400 and 200 meters.
跑
Go.
闪光灯闪耀着 选手们冲出来了
Flashbulbs flashing. Ato boldon away last.
这是弗兰克弗 雷德里克斯
Here's Frank Fredericks.
紧随其后的 是迈克尔 约翰逊
And here comes Michael Johnson.
差不多是这个速度 我猜
About the right speed, I guess.
- 是吗 -是啊
- Yeah? - Yeah.
他们正在接近赛道的冲刺阶段
They're approaching the top of the straightaway.
迈克尔 约翰逊一马当先
Michael Johnson reaching deep.
时间要到了吗
What are we clocking?
他遥遥领先
He has the lead.
迈克尔 约翰逊马上就要到达终点了
Michael Johnson is closing on the finish!
迈克尔 约翰逊赢得了金牌
Michael Johnson running for gold!
同时也载入了奥林匹运动史
and into Olympic history!
他打破了由自己保持的记录
He destroys his own record!
- 时间 - 六分钟
- Time. - Six minutes.
好的 我们知道第二个报警电话是在12点
Okay, we know the second 911 call was placed at 12...
58分
58.
从这个投币电话打出的
From the pay phone that was right here.
我们也知道理查德当时在公园里
We also know that Richard was inside the park
在距离爆炸点附近的灯塔 当时是12点
near the sound and light tower at 12...
57分
57.
当比尔 米勒报告发现不明背包的时候
When Bill Miller called the backpack in.
他没法这样来回
He would've had to cover the distance in...
在一分钟之内 所以不是他做的
one minute. So he couldn't have done it.
可以骑自行车 我猜
Could've ridden a bike, I guess.
骑车来回 不可能
There and back? No.
真的不是他做的
He really didn't do this.
不是他
No.
这家伙被诬陷了
This kid's getting railroaded.
我们要帮助他
We're gonna help this guy.
我们要帮助他 他被诬陷了
We're gonna help this guy. This kid's getting railroaded.
妈耶
Holy...
你别说话 我来说
You don't talk. I talk.
他们只会东看西看
They're just gonna look around.
你家里有枪吗
You got any guns in the house?
有 我们曾经在佐治亚待过
Yeah, we're in Georgia.
当然了 去拿来吧
Yeah, of course you do. Go get 'em.
把枪摆在床上这样我们就能看到这些枪
Lay 'em on your bed so we can see 'em.
我们不想发生任何意外
We don't want any surprises.
有多少记者要进来
How many of 'em are coming in here?
呃
Uh...
有一些些吧
There's a couple.
他们能把鞋子脱了放在门边吗
Can they leave their shoes outside the door?
我可以跟他们说 波比
Well, I could ask 'em, bobi.
但是我觉得他们不会遵守
I don't know if they would oblige.
天呐
Oh, god.
我的天
Oh, good lord.
呃
Uh...
你这是在准备跟僵尸大战吗
Were you expecting a zombie invasion or something?
不是准备跟僵尸大战
No, I wasn't expecting zombies.
是准备跟鹿大战 我打猎
I expect deer. I hunt.
你打猎 行吧
You hunt? Okay.
雷达 让我跟你讲清楚
Radar, let me explain something to you.
你现在最大的罪行
All you're guilty of right now
就是看起来像那种会恐怖炸弹袭击的人
is looking like the kinda guy who might set off a bomb.
但是你在做的这些事情
But everything you do
只会加深那种看法然后让我们死的很惨
that promotes that image is gonna hang us.
抱歉 我用词不太好
Sorry. Poor choice of words.
外面的那些混蛋
Those jackals out there,
想要你被大卸八块
They want your ass on a chopping block.
所以你这里到底还有没有
Is there anything else odd or quirky
什么奇奇怪怪的或者非常变态的东西 我还不知道的
or fucking weird that I'm gonna discover today?
可能有吧
Yeah, kinda.
我还没
I haven't...
最近几年我还没有付我的所得税
I haven't paid my taxes in about... a couple years.
- 噢 - 这真是越来越棒了呢
- Oh. - This gets better and better.
枪枪枪 我讨厌枪
Guns, guns, guns. I hate guns.
每次理查去打猎我都会说
Every time Richard goes huntin', I say,
别拖一只死鹿到家里
"don't you dare drag a dead bambI in here.
我不想吃小鹿
"I don't wanna eat bambi."
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
理查德还是哈伯沙姆县
Richard, when he was deputy
治安官副手的时候
with the Habersham county sheriff's,
他在满分100的射击测试中得了98分
He got 98 out of 100 on his shootin' test.
那真是了不起
It was awesome.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
真棒
That's great.
- 好了 - 天啊
- Okay. - Dear god.
你不说话 我来说 重复一遍
You don't talk. I talk. Say it.
我不说话
I don't talk.
但是我想让那些人知道
But I want those guys to know that
我也是执法人员 跟他们一样
I'm law enforcement, too. Just like them.
看到了吗
See, right there?
这是说话
That's talking.
我们不想要你说话 好吗
That's what we don't want, okay?
你真是选了个好律师 理查
You picked the right lawyer, Richard.
呃
Ugh.
你都准备好了吗
We all set?
- 是啊 - 好的 进来吧
- Yeah. - All right, let's go. Come on.
我们从后面开始
Let's start in the back.
带进来 快一点 大家按数字顺序来
Bring it in. Let's go. By the numbers, everybody.
数字顺序来
By the numbers.
等下
Hold on.
好
Oh... okay.
行
Okay.
好吧 你们就进来拿走一切吧
Yeah, so, you guys go ahead and take everything.
拿走地毯什么的 只要你需要
Take the carpet, whatever you need.
我也是执法人员 所以我明白的
I'm law enforcement, too, so I get it.
但是你要知道不管你拿走什么
Just know that whatever you take,
都只会证明我是无辜的
It's just gonna prove that I didn't do anything.
我们不是第一天做这个事情
Yeah, we've done this before.
你是律师吗 布莱恩先生
You'll be counsel, Mr. Bryant?
计划上是这样的
That's the plan, yeah.
好的 如果你要留下来的话
All right, well, if you're gonna stay here,
你得戴上这个
You're gonna have to put these on.
是的 戴上手套穿上靴子
Yeah, let's go. Gloves and booties.
好
Yeah.
你听到他说的了 靴子还有手套
You heard the man. Booties and gloves.
沃森 他们要带走我的特百惠
Watson, they're emptying my tupperware.
没事 让他们去
All right, let's play ball right now.
我们早晚会拿回来的
We'll get it back.
如果你需要帮助来找到什么东西的话
If y'all need help finding anything,
尽管来告诉我们
feel free to ask one of us.
我们会来帮助你的
We can help.
只是想帮忙而已
Just trying to help.
在里面呢
It's in there.
你有读过这本书吗
You ever read that book?
讲了很多警察的规章制度
Got a lot in it about police procedure.
很不错的 还有点争议性
It's a good one. It's kinda controversial.
很不错的一本书
It's a good book.
是很不错的一本书
噢
Oh, uh...
我可以来帮你
I can help you with that.
那些可是我的宝贝啊
I babysit with those.
对了实际上如果你们能在外面
You know what? Actually, it might be easier if you guys
等我们弄完的话
just waited outside
- 一切会简单很多 - 好主意
- while we did our jobs. - Good idea.
- 好的 我们去外面等 - 谢谢
- Yeah, let's do that. - Thank you.
我们去外面等 理查
Let's do that, Richard.
赶紧离开这个地方
Let's get the hell out of here.
谢谢
Thank you.
约翰逊 罗萨里奥 找到什么了吗
Johnson, Rosario, anything?
我们说好什么来着？
What was the agreement?
说好我不说话
That I wouldn't talk. Yup.
是啊 你做了什么呢
Yeah, what'd you do?
我说话了
I talked.
他们想油炸了你
They wanna fry you.
你知道吗 你知道的对吧
You understand that? You know that, right?
在这里的所有记者警察都想油炸了你
Everyone here wants to fry you.
你就是一片小培根
You're a little piece of bacon.
好吧 换个话题
Well, on a lighter note,
你也从没告诉我
You never did tell me the name of the firm
你搬去公司的名字
you moved to and whatnot.
我自己开的
I opened my own.
为什么要这么做
What made you do something like that?
公司意味着有合伙人
Firms mean partners,
合伙人认为他们可以对你指手画脚
And partners think they can tell you who to be.
我不太喜欢被人说教
I don't care much for being dictated to.
嘿！你没有权力这么做
Hey! You have no right.
- 回来 - 妈妈 怎么了
- Come back here. - Mama, what's wrong?
他们拿走了我的内衣
They went through my underthings.
他们还想要我们受多少的侮辱
How much indignity do they want us to take?
波比
All right, Bobi.
嘿 等等 伙计们 借过
Hey, hold on, fellas. Excuse me.
妈妈 嘿
Mama, hey...
波比 等一下 伙计们
Bobi. Excuse me, fellas.
波比 等一下
Bobi. Excuse me.
他们拿走了你什么东西
What did they take from you?
等一下 等一下
Hold on now. Hold on.
波比 让我来帮你处理这件事
Bobi, let me take care of it for you.
我能来你帮你处理吗
Can I take care of it for you?
我会拿回来的
I'm gonna go get 'em.
我会拿回来的 等一下
I'm gonna go get 'em. Excuse me.
你能告诉我们什么消息吗
What can you share with us?
显然他们发现了
They found
一些非常危险的连裤袜
Some really dangerous pantyhose, apparently.
- 认真的吗 - 是啊
- Seriously? - Yeah.
理查德
Richard.
过来一下 我想跟你探探
Come here for a sec. I wanna talk to you.
- 进来吧 - 是的先生
- Come on inside. - Yes, sir.
我能帮你什么
What can I help with?
先进来吧 一会儿就好
Just come on inside. Just for a second.
他们从房子里拿走了什么
What did they pull out of the house?
是他做的吗 沃森
Did he do it, Watson?
不他没有
No, he did not.
理查德朱维尔是一个无辜的人 他是个英雄
Richard Jewell is an innocent man. He's a hero.
如果他是无辜的话为什么联邦调查局在这里
If he's innocent, then why is the FBI here?
我们欢迎联邦调查局 我们很高兴他们来了
We welcome the FBI. We're glad they're here.
不 你没有
No, you don't.
你知道我说的是实话 凯西
You know that's not true, Kathy.
我能看看那些盒子吗
Can I see those boxes, please?
好吧 接下来呢
All right, here's what we're gonna do.
我会把电话给你
I'm gonna hand you this phone...
给了你之后
and when I do,
你要等到哔哔声
You're gonna wait till the beep
然后你要对着电话说
And then you're gonna say into it,
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
"there's a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes."
对不起 为什么
I'm sorry. Why?
我们需要一个声音样本
We need a voice exemplar.
需要你重复说几次
Like you to say it a few times.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
"There's a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes."
这可能是还你清白的唯一办法
It might be the only way to clear your name.
我真的想帮你们
I do wanna help y'all.
我也是执法人员
I'm law enforcement, too.
那你应该知道证据
Well, yeah. Then you should know how
采集是什么吧
evidentiary this is, right?
所以 说 在世纪公园有一个炸弹
So, "there's a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes."
三十分钟 好吧
"30 minutes." Okay.
- 在哔声之后 - 是的
- After the beep? - Yeah.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
There is a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes.
好的 再说一次 大声一点
Okay, one more time. Just a little louder.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
There is a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes.
很好 你能再说一次吗
Okay, that's great. Can you do it one more time?
连续多说几次吧
Maybe let's do a series. We'll do a couple in a row.
好吧
All right.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
There is a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
There is a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
There is a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
There is a bomb in centennial park.
你有三十分钟时间
You have 30 minutes.
在世纪公园有一个炸弹
There is a bomb in centennial park.
你他妈的在逗我吗 不不不 你不能跟他说话
Are you fucking kidding me? No, no, you don't talk to him.
他们说这是标准程序
It's standard procedure, they said.
不 是个屁啊
No, hell it is.
- 在俄罗斯 - 布莱恩先生 听着
- in Russia. - Mr. Bryant, listen.
你的委托人自愿的
Your client volunteered this.
放屁 或许你可以做这个 或许你不行
Oh, bullshit. Maybe you can do this. Maybe you can't.
但是今天不行 我们走吧 理查德
You're not doing it today. Let's go, Richard.
- 我们走 - 我告诉他们
- Let's go. - I told them
如果这么做可以洗脱我的罪名的话
I'm doing it if it helps clear my name.
- 我们走 今天不行 - 你委托人同意了的
- Let's go! Not today. - Your client agreed to this.
我要起诉你
I'm gonna sue your ass
- 故意违反 - 好吧
- for intentional violation... - Okay.
宪法赋予他的权力
of his constitutional rights.
好吧
Okay.
我要搞得你们全部都被革职
I'm having all this shit excluded.
你们这些家伙都是混蛋
You guys are full of shit.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我们拿到证据了
We got it.
晚安
Have a good night.
他们要拿吸尘器干什么
What do they want with the vacuum cleaner?
好了 我们结束了
All right. We're done here.
理查德
Richard?
我没事 我没事
I'm fine. yeah, I'm fine.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你先进去吧
Let's get you inside.
戴夫 你能给她拿点喝的吗
Dave, can you get her something to drink?
- 拿点水什么的 - 没问题
- Maybe some water? - Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sure.
怎么了
What's going on?
没事
It's nothing.
我没事
I'm fine.
他们拿走了我所有的特百惠塑料餐具
They took all my tupperware.
他们要特百惠干什么啊
What would they need with my tupperware?
那个炸弹犯用特百惠塑料餐具固定住钉子
The bomber used tupperware to hold the nails.
很正常
That's standard.
那跟你又有什么关系呢
Well, what does that have to do with you?
他拿走了我的宝贝影带
And they took my babysittin' tapes.
我的迪士尼电影
My disney movies.
我觉得他们可能想看看
Yeah, I think they did that because they wanted to see
我们是否在磁带上录了什么
If we might've recorded something on the tapes,
比如政治声明什么的
Like a political statement or something.
你为什么一直要维护这些人
Why do you keep defending these people?
这不是在维护他们 只是解释
I'm not defending. I'm just explaining.
那就闭嘴
Well, stop it!
-她来了 你好 -你好
- Hey, there she is. Hey. - Hi.
-你好吗 -你好
- How you doin'? - Hello.
这位是娜德雅 她是
This is Nadya. She's, uh...
她是我的上级领导
She tells me what to do.
我来拿着吧 谢谢你
Here. Let me take that. That's very nice of you.
我觉得你们可能想吃点晚饭
I thought you might want some dinner.
上帝保佑你
Bless your heart.
-谢谢 -不客气
- Thank you. - Of course.
你好 我是理查德
Hi, I'm Richard.
我刚才怎么跟你说的来着 理查
What did I tell you about talking, Rich?
天哪 我想我不能说话了
Oh, god, yeah. I guess I can't talk anymore.
来吧 理查德 你不能再躲着了
Come on, Richard, you can't hide anymore.
理查德 就回答一个问题
Richard, one question. That's all.
是你干的吗
Did you do it?
理查德 你造了多少个炸弹
Richard, how many bombs have you made?
FBI从你家拿走了什么 理查德
What did the FBI take out of your house, Richard?
手榴弹吗
Hand grenade?
你拿手榴弹干嘛
What do you got a hand grenade for?
这是中空的
Yeah, it's hollowed out.
是个镇纸
It's a paperweight.
我从军需品店买来的
I bought it from a military surplus store.
-行吧 -但也没什么
- Yeah. - But it's nothing.
天哪 不愧是你
Christ, of course you did.
长凳碎片
Piece of the bench?
碎片
Splintered piece of...
这是什么意思 那是什么
What does that mean? What is that?
我从犯罪现场
Yeah, I took a small piece of the bench
拿走了一小片长凳
from the crime scene.
从爆炸的地方吗
From where the bomb was?
这是个纪念品 纪念品
It's a souvenir. a memento.
为什么这么做
What'd you do that for?
我觉得那天晚上值得纪念
I think it was a pretty memorable night
因为我做了了不起的事
where I did something pretty great.
所以我觉得这值得保存
So, I thought maybe that was worth holding on to.
好吧
Wow. Okay.
很好
Nice.
-你好 -你好
- Hey. - Hey.
他们现在想取走你的头发和手印
They want your hair now, and your palm prints.
祝你愉快
Good times.
进来吧
Come in.
拔下来25根 收起来25根
25 pulled, 25 collected.
告诉你 哪怕你有搜查令
I tell you, you might have a warrant for this,
但如果你这么对我
But if you were to do this to me,
我一定会揍你
You'd have to fight me. Oh!
揍得你满地找牙那种
You'd have to beat the shit outta me!
你这个律师不是很像律师啊
Not very lawyerly of you, counselor.
好吧
Yeah, well...
我们能不能在我妈妈回家之前弄完
Can we just get this over with before my mama comes back?
我不想让她看到这些
I'd like her not to see this.
告诉我 理查德
Tell me, Richard,
你仍然以执法为傲吗
You still proud to be law enforcement?
你知道吗 或许我可以做的更好一点
You know what? Maybe if I did my job a little better,
人们就可以离得足够远
And got people far enough away,
那我现在就不会坐在这里了
Then I wouldn't be sittin' here right now.
好吧 他真是个奇葩 伙计们做的不错啊
Yeah, he's a real monster. Boy, you guys nailed it.
你们这些笨蛋还没计算
Have you dummies done the math yet
到公用电话的距离吗
on the call from the pay phone?
听着 去他的公用电话
Hey, listen, fuck the pay phone! Okay?
我的客户那天晚上在公园
My clients were the people in the park that night
他们的头不该被炸飞的
That didn't deserve to get their fuckin' heads blown off.
你知道吗 我为你们这些家伙感到抱歉
You know, I actually feel sorry for you guys.
一旦真的炸弹犯再出动
When the real bomber does it again,
全国都会问 FBI在哪里
And the country asks, "where was the FBI?"
你们就会说 我们当时忙着
You're gonna say, "we were busy
给理查德 朱维尔取样头发呢
Getting hair samples from Richard Jewell."
-我这里好了 -都好了吗 很好
- I'm done here. - All set? Great.
很好
Oh, good.
好吧 谢谢你了理查德
Well, Richard, thank you very much
谢谢你的专业的考虑
for your professional consideration.
你懂得 警察之间那种
You know, cop to cop.
我们是FBI
"we're the FBI."
我懂了你的警察之间 在这
I got your cop to cop. Right here.
门在那里
There's the door.
找到了 谢谢
Found it. Thank you.
理查德 我们需要对这些混蛋
Richard, we need to be a little less, uh...
少一点关怀
solicitous and a little more
多一些愤怒
righteous with these assjacks.
我是觉得 只是头发 还会长回来的
I mean, it's just hairs. They'll grow back. It's fine.
你说什么
What'd you say?
只是头发 还会长
They're just hairs. They'll grow back.
只是头发 兄弟
They're just hair. Hey!
你为什么不像我一样生气呢
Why doesn't this shit make you as angry as it makes me?
我很生气
I am angry.
你别骗我了
You could have fooled me.
你生气吗
You're angry?
当然
'Course I am.
我都不知道生气这个词
I don't know if "angry"
是否可以表达我的愤怒
is even a big enough word for how I feel.
来吧
Come on.
那就不要像门垫似的了
Then stop being such a doormat.
不要当他们的好朋友了
Stop trying to be their best friend.
你知道吗 他们在外面嘲笑你 你知道
You know, they're making fun of you out there. You know
- 他们怎么称呼你吗 -我知道的
- what they're calling you? - I know that!
我知道他说的警察之间是什么意思
I know what it means when he says "cop to cop."
他当然不是那个意思
He doesn't mean cop to cop.
他觉得我是面团宝宝
He thinks I'm the Pillsbury Doughboy.
你真的知道吗 别骗我了
Do ya? could have fooled me.
我以为你俩订婚了呢
I thought you guys were gonna get engaged.
理查德 你要是现在吃饼干
Hey! Richard! You go for a cookie right now,
我就把你手剁下来塞进屁股里
I'm gonna chop off your hands and shove 'em up your ass!
你吃个饼干试试看 混蛋
Try eating a cookie then, fucker.
你为什么要当我的律师
Why'd you wanna represent me and be my lawyer?
你看上去好像需要帮助
Hey, you looked like you needed some help.
你看起来像是需要卖书赚钱
You look like you might've needed money from a book deal.
那我问你 你为什么选我
Well, let me ask you, why'd you pick me?
电话簿上律师有很多
There's a lot of lawyers in the phone book.
你为什么选了我
What'd you pick me for?
我选你是因为你是唯一一个
I picked you because you were the only one
在美国小企业管理局
at the U.S. small business admin bureau
没把我当五岁孩子的人 没叫我
who didn't treat me like a 5-year-old, and call me
零食袋 飞艇 米其林人
"bag of snacks" and "blimp," "michelin man,"
还有面团宝宝
And "Pillsbury Doughboy."
你是唯一
You're the only one who treated me
把我当人看的
like a human being!
你现在冲我大喊大叫
And now you're just yelling at me,
让我去成为别人
telling me to be somebody that I'm not!
我不知道怎么成那个样
I don't know how to be that guy!
你才是那样的 不是我
You're that guy! I'm me!
什么
What?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我的天
Oh, my lord.
他们怎么可以这样
How can they do that?
很简单
It's easy,
因为你不介意
Because you don't matter.
所以才这样
That's how come.
我们要离开
We need to go!
你们快走
Move!
你们必须走
You guys gotta go!
我们需要疏散
We need to evacuate!
杜契斯先生
Mr. Dutchess.
有空吗
You got a minute?
有
I got that.
走吧
There you go.
-我能吃完饭吗 -不能
- Can I finish my food? - Nope. mmm.
好吧
Hmm, that's good.
他们认为
They've decided that since
你不可能自己给911打电话
you can't have placed the 911 call yourself,
所以你必须有个同伙
That you must've had a partner.
他们觉得你的同伙就是你的同性恋男友
They think your partner must be your homosexual boyfriend,
他们觉得可能是我
which they decided is probably me.
什么
What?
他们让我带上监听器
They asked me to wear a wire.
我让他们滚蛋 我说你是个英雄
I told them to shove it. I said you were a hero.
他们说 如果他真的是英雄
And they said, "well, if he really is a hero,
那他没什么好担心的
then he's got nothing to worry about
你也不用担心了
and neither do you."
他们还告诉我 你有个佐治亚州调查局的兄弟
They also told me that, uh, one of your GBI buddies,
就是过来的时候
you know, the one you made lasagna for
你做了千层面那个
when he came over...
是 米勒
Yeah, Miller.
好吧
Yeah.
他也带了监听器
He was wearing a wire, too.
他从你这录了不少
He's got a lot on you.
还有一件事
There's, uh, one other thing. um...
他们问我有没有造管制炸弹的经验
They asked me if I'd ever had any experience with pipe bombs
我只能实话说了
And I had to tell them the truth.
你知道吗 那种小的
You know, the little ones.
我小时候在弗吉尼亚西部
We used to drop them down gopher holes when I was a kid
-常常扔进地鼠洞 - 天哪 大卫
- in west Virginia. - David... lord.
我告诉他们这之后几年我才认识的理查德
I told them this was years before I even met Richard.
我说了好几次
I told them a couple times.
还是
Still...
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
只是
It's...
这
It...
没事
It's okay. yeah.
没错
Yep.
没事的
It's okay.
我做的
I did what was...
关
Hey. hey, turn...
你在干什么
Come on! What are you doing?
我们不能在他们监听的时候
We can't be watching movies with bombs and explosions
看有炸弹和爆炸的电影
when they're listening.
来
Come...
你们都
Y'all...
我只是想做正确的事
I'm... I'm trying to do the right thing.
对吗
Right?
伙计们 他们没有在监听吗
Guys... are they not listening?
妈妈 很抱歉
Hey, mama, I'm sorry.
妈妈 我错了
Mama, I'm sorry.
求你了
Please?
妈妈出来吧
Mama, come on out.
你想看什么就看什么
We can watch whatever you wanna watch.
我不介意
Uh, I don't mind.
妈妈求你
Mama, please...
我什么都不说了
I won't say nothing about anything.
求你出来吧
Just come on out.
妈妈 对不起
Mama, I'm sorry. I'm...
求你了
Please?
妈妈求你了
Mama, please?
我知道的
I know.
-我很害怕 理查德 -我
- I'm scared, Richard. - I'm...
我陪着你呢
I'm right there with you.
没事的
It's all right.
我不知道如何保护你不被那些人伤害
I don't know how to protect you from these people.
你知道吗
Hey, you know...
你不用保护我的
You know what? you don't have to protect me.
我来保护你 我来
I do the protecting. I do.
就是这样
Yep.
来吧 出来吧
Come on. come on out.
你就坐下来 想看什么就看
You just sit down. You watch whatever you wanna watch.
我不在乎
I don't care.
很抱歉我冲你大喊大叫了
And I'm sorry I yelled.
她曾经为她的儿子
Yeah, she's had about, mmm, three days
骄傲了三天
to be proud of her son,
然后就被他们毁了
and then taken away from her.
这是不对的
Yep. That ain't right.
抱歉 理查德
I'm sorry, Richard.
你准备好反击了吗
You ready to start fighting back?
嗯
Yeah.
理查德
Richard!
你是来自首的吗
Are you here to turn yourself in?
不知道为什么不让FBI做这个
Don't see why we can't just let the FBI do this.
你相信他们的结果吗
Uh, you trust them with the results?
放心就好 深呼吸
You're in good hands here. Just breathe.
理查德谁让你来做测谎的
Richard, whose idea was it for you to take a polygraph test?
沃森让我来的
Watson's.
你觉得你会怎么
How do you think you'll do on it?
很好
Fine.
你知道是谁把炸弹放进奥林匹克公园的吗
Do you know who put that bomb in Olympic park?
不 我不知道是谁把炸弹放到世纪公园的
No, I do not know who planted the bomb in centennial park.
或许我们可以谈一谈
Hey, maybe we better talk...
不用了 他通过了
Nah. He passed.
最高级别的那种 没有说谎
Highest level. No deception indicated.
天哪
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, my god.
谢谢你了
Thanks, man. Hey.
谢谢
Thank you.
看看你
Hey. Look at you, huh?
你做到了兄弟
You did it, man.
对 我们做到了
Yeah, we did it.
你做到了 做到了
You did it. You did it.
在这上面我们要坚定
We must be firm in this.
我们不能被恐怖行为吓倒
We cannot be intimidated by acts of terror.
我想感谢英勇的安保人员
I want to thank the brave security personnel.
60岁以上的妇女中可卡因用量增加
Cocaine use is up from women in their sixties.
是吗
Yeah?
-是啊 看看 -他们真幸运
- Yeah. Look at that. - Lucky them.
我去 是朱维尔
Holy shit, it's Jewell.
你是凯西 斯克鲁格斯吗
Is that Kathy Scruggs?
你好
Hey.
这就是幕后的样子吗
Is this what it's like behind the curtain?
-这是理查德 朱维尔 -你好
- Richard Jewell here. - Hello.
我们正想让你撤回新闻
We're just about to go demand a retraction.
然后去买汉堡 一起吗
Then we're gonna go get a hamburger. You wanna come?
-这样吗 -没错
- Is that right? - Yeah.
我认为
This is, I mean,
这是顶级科幻小说
This is, like, top-rate science fiction.
炸弹嫌疑犯渴望成为焦点
"bomb suspect sought limelight."
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你以为你是谁啊
Who the hell do you think you are?
布莱恩特先生 我只是在报道事实
Mr. Bryant, what I do is I report the facts.
你是在引导大众
You lead the public, is what you do.
我报道的是事实
I report the facts.
事实
The facts?
没错 我就是这么做的
That's right. That's what I do.
-你无知 -什么
- You ignorant... - Excuse me?
-傲慢 自负 -什么
- arrogant, ambitious... - Excuse me?
你是怎么得到这份工作的
How did you get this job?
-怎么得到这份工作的 -没错
- How'd I get this job? - Yeah.
布莱恩特先生 如果你有问题可以向FBI提
Mr. Bryant, if you have an issue, you can take it up
是他们在调查你的客户
with the FBI for investigating your client.
胡说八道
Oh, bullshit.
与我无关好吗
It has nothing to do with me. All right?
我只是听到了事实
What I do is, I hear the facts,
报道了事实 这是我的责任所在
I report them. That is my responsibility.
事实 那真相呢
The facts? What about the truth, huh?
我的原则就是要报道事实
My guiding principle is to report the facts.
什么狗屁原则
What fucking principles?
你应该遵守的原则现在就站在我旁边
This isn't a principle standing next to me.
去你的原则吧
Fuck your principle.
这个人他叫理查德 朱维尔
This man's name is Richard Jewell.
他救人性命 他是个英雄
He's a hero. He saved lives.
你闯进来 跟我说这些 简直是不可理喻
You're unbelievable, just coming in here.
我不可理喻 你有没有搞错
I'm unbelievable? Do you have any idea
你明不明白你到底做了些什么
what kinda wildfire you started?
你毁了这个人的一切
You've ruined this man's life.
- 也许你欠他一句道歉 - 听着
- Maybe you owe him an apology. - Listen...
你看这样如何
How about that?
朱维尔 呃 先生 我
Mr... Mr. Jewell, I...
你知道你就是个 什么
You know, you are a... what?
我说 对于你和你的母亲所经历的这一切
I said I'm sorry
我感到抱歉
for what you and your mother have gone through.
得了吧 你就是新闻工作者里的败类
Oh, you are a miserable excuse for a journalist.
- 你就是个蛀虫 - 你知道吗
- You're a parasite. - You know what...
为了篇该死的报道不择手段
anything to sell a goddamn paper, you know that?
你简直是在无事生非
Why don't you go chase another ambulance?
去你妈的
Kiss my ass.
- 他简直疯了 - 是啊 所以大家还是抓紧工作吧
- He's out of order. - Y'all can go back to work.
没什么好看的
There's nothing really to watch here.
你们做自己的事情就好了
You can just keep doing your jobs.
哇
Wow.
不是他做的
He didn't do it.
去他妈的
Oh, fuck.
你还真有胆量坐在这里啊
You got a lot of fucking nerve sitting here.
朱维尔没有打过那通电话
Jewell couldn't have made the call.
距离不对
The math is wrong.
我从现场走到电话亭
I covered the distance from the site to the phones.
他不可能来得及打那通电话
There's no way he would have made it in time.
是的 我们知道
Yeah, we know.
你们知道
You know?
他有同伙
He had an accomplice.
同伙
An accomplice?
当然 不能有吗
Sure. Why not?
那炸弹袭击者一人独自作案的侧写怎么说
What about the lone bomber profile?
崇拜者模仿警察 还有同伙吗
The wannabe cop? With an accomplice?
好吧 首先
Well, first of all,
侧写只是一个初始画像
Profiles are always just a jumping-off point.
还记得吗 俄克拉荷马城爆炸案就有两个炸弹犯
Oklahoma city had two bombers, if you remember.
好吧 所以是谁干的呢 同伙是谁呢
Okay, so who did it? Who is it?
你对我做了这些之后 还觉得我会告诉你吗
Like I'm gonna tell you after the way you burned me.
好吧
Fine.
那我就只写对朱维尔不利的案情
I'll just write that the case against Jewell
已经开始动摇了
is starting to weaken.
这些糟糕的事实等等 看看事情究竟会如何吧
Bad facts, et cetera. See how that goes.
你知道吗 我虽然不确定你为什么会这么想
You know what? I'm not sure where you get this idea
就是我会为你工作 或者说我们合作
That I work for you, or that we work together.
我甚至不知道我他妈为什么要跟你说话
I don't even know why I'm fucking talking to you.
我知道 我需要你 你也需要我
I know why. And you need me just as much as I need you.
你知道吗 亲爱的
You know what, sweetheart?
你对我来说屁用没有
I don't need you a goddamn bit.
再来一杯
Can I have one more, please?
我旁边这位是波比 朱维尔
Next to me is Bobi Jewell...
理查德 朱维尔的母亲
Mother of Richard Jewell.
或许是造化弄人
By some savage twist of fate,
不实地冠以谋杀和故意伤害的罪名
and falsely accused of murder and mayhem.
起诉她儿子的人
Her son's accusers
正是当今世界最强的两股势力
are two of the most powerful forces in the world today.
美国政府和美国媒体
The united states government and the media.
在过去的四周
For the past four weeks,
这些可怕的势力联合在一起
these horrific forces have combined
让她生不如死
to make her daily existence a living hell.
如我所说
As I speak,
他们仍在剥夺着她的人生
they continue to crush the very life out of her
伤害着她唯一的儿子
and her only son.
芭芭拉 朱维尔
I introduce Barbara Jewell,
世纪公园炸弹袭击的第113位受害者
The 113th victim of the centennial bombing.
我叫芭芭拉 朱维尔
My name is Barbara Jewell.
我是一名理赔协调员
I am employed as a claims coordinator
我在当地的保险公司
with a local insurance agency,
已经工作13年了
and I have worked there for 13 years.
大概四周前
Approximately four weeks ago,
奥林匹克公园的炸弹
over 100 people were injured
导致超过100人受伤
and two people lost their lives
2人死亡
As a result of the Olympic park bombing.
我的心与这些受害者及他们的家属同在
My heart goes out to these victims and their families.
我精疲力竭
I am so very drained.
我向上天请求 祈祷
I hope and pray to god
希望所有人都能远离这种苦难
that nobody ever has to go through this again.
我认为在场的所有人
I do not think any of you
都想象不出我们的生活变成什么样了
can even begin to imagine what our lives are like.
在媒体的口中
The media has portrayed my son...
我的儿子实施了这起犯罪
as the person who has committed this crime.
他们剥夺了我们的一切隐私
They have taken all privacy from us.
让我们的生活不得安宁
They have taken all peace.
他们监视 并拍下我们做的每一件事
They watch and photograph everything we do.
正如媒体一样
Like the media,
FBI监视着他的一举一动
The FBI follows his every move
也一直监视着我们的住所
and watches my home constantly.
凭什么
And why?
我的儿子
My son...
我的儿子何其无辜
My son is innocent.
理查德不是奥林匹克公园的炸弹犯
Richard is not the Olympic park bomber.
理查德不是一个谋杀犯
Richard is not a murderer.
他救了这些人的性命
He saved people's lives.
总统大人 请听我一言 伸出援手
Please hear me, Mr. president, and help me.
只有你有能力终止这场噩梦
You have the power to end this nightmare.
我的儿子是一个英雄
My son is a hero.
我相信FBI已经知道了
I think the FBI knows that by now.
如果他们打算还我儿子清白
If they do not intend to charge my son,
请告诉我们
Please tell us.
告诉这个世界
Please tell the world.
总统大人
Mr. president.
请您为我儿子正名
Please clear my son's name.
好了
Okay.
你真的很棒
You did good.
理查德
Richard.
妈妈
Oh, mama.
谢谢你为我做的这些
Oh, thank you for doing that.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
对不起 我没有忍住
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I cried.
我本来不想哭的
I... I didn't mean to cry.
不 这很好 简直不能用好来形容
No, you did real good. You did better than good.
准备好了吗
You ready?
告诉他们你到底是谁
Let's go show them who you are.
哦 天呐
Oh, god.
终于结束了
I'm so glad that's over.
你做的很好
You did good.
好吧
All right.
先生们 请坐
Gentlemen, please have a seat.
我们马上就来
We'll be right with you.
好吧 我来告诉你都要做什么
All right, let me tell you how it's gonna go.
他们首先会要求与我见面 约法三章
They're gonna ask to see me first, set the ground rules.
我必须让他们知道我不是同性恋
I wanna make sure they know I'm not gay.
理查德 我觉得我们有更重要的事情要做
Richard, I think we got bigger fish to fry,
但是 你会有机会告诉他们这个的
But, uh, you'll get the chance to tell them that.
这点是肯定的
I'm sure.
肖探员
Agent shaw.
敢不敢去看看他有没有士力架
Dare you to see if he's got any snickers.
有点饿了
Kinda hungry.
你知道1001是什么吗 雷达
You know what a 1001 is, Radar?
是的 先生 就是对一个联邦探员撒谎
Yes, sir. It's lying to a federal agent.
这是重罪
It's a felony.
你在这有任何不实之言
You say anything in there that isn't true,
他们会把你丢进监狱
they can put you in jail
根本都不需要证明你是个炸弹犯
without ever proving you're a bomber.
嘿
Hey.
不知道说什么的时候 就什么都别说
You don't know what to say, you say nothing.
你可以要求休息5分钟
You ask for a five-minute break,
你可以问我
You consult with me.
你不要即兴发挥
You do not improvise.
懂了吗
You got that?
懂了
Yes, sir.
那如果你不知道该说什么 怎么办
So if you don't know what to say, what do you do?
- 屁都不放一个 - 没错
- I don't say a damn thing. - That's right.
布莱恩特先生
Mr. Bryant?
需要帮助吗
Can I help you?
我就是看看
I was taking a look.
你们打算怎么解决这件事情
How do you guys wanna handle this?
是这样 我们会问你们一些问题
Well, we're gonna ask you some questions,
需要你们给出答案
and you're gonna give us some answers.
怎么样
How's that sound?
好的
Okay.
听起来不错
Sounds good.
我去叫他
I'll go get him.
准备好了吗 伙计
Hey, you ready, boyo?
好了
Yeah.
我觉得可以了
I think so. Yeah.
不是 我是说准备好
No, I mean ready.
不要低眉顺眼 逆来顺受
Look at these guys not as suspect to agent,
要不卑不亢 你与他们是平等的
But as cop to cop.
不用对他们太客气了
Don't give them any more deference than they're due.
更不要叫他们长官
And don't keep calling them "sir."
好的 但他们总归代表美国政府
Yeah, well, they're still the United States government.
不 他们代表不了美国政府
No, they aren't the United States government.
他们就是三个
They're just three pricks
为美国政府工作的混蛋
who work for the United States government.
你能明白这之间的差别
You understand the difference?
这里面坐着的人 没有人好过你
Nobody in that room is a better man than you.
懂吗
You understand?
来吧
Come on.
你没问题的
You'll be fine.
这儿 就坐这儿
That's it. Sit right there.
这儿吗
Right here?
是的
Yeah.
感谢您的到来
Thank you for joining us.
朱维尔先生
Uh, Mr. Jewell,
我们有几个问题
We've got a few questions,
关于1996年7月27日的事件
regarding the events of Iuly 27th, 1996,
你应该知道
As you probably know.
尤其是世纪公园爆炸案
Specifically the bombing in centennial park.
朱维尔先生 你是否发现你自己
Mr. Jewell, you ever find yourself
进入过一个名叫糖果小贩的糖果乐园的网站
accessing a internet site called Candyman's Candyland
上面有一些无政府主义者的食谱
regarding the contents of the anarchist cookbook?
没有
No, I have not.
但你接受警员培训时
But you do have police training
培训过如何处理爆炸物 对吗
in handling explosives?
这个问题问过了 也回答过了
Asked and answered.
你收集过爆炸管的碎片吗
Did you ever collect any pieces of pipe
在世纪公园的建筑中的
From, uh, the construction of centennial park?
不 我没有
No, I did not.
你记得在公园有和谁说过
Do you remember telling anybody at the park, uh,
现在 抓紧给我拍照吧
"take my picture now,
因为马上我就要出名了
because pretty soon I'm gonna be famous"?
没有 长官
No, sir.
真的吗
Really?
你确定
You sure about that?
百分之百确定
100%.
那你有没有说过
How about, did you say,
我在去亚特兰大的路上
"I'm on my way to Atlanta.
外面马上乱成一锅粥了
It's gonna be a mess out there"?
我指的是外面的交通堵塞
I was referring to the traffic jams.
朱维尔先生
Mr. Jewell,
你为什么特别想驻守在
Why specifically did you want to be stationed
灯光塔附近
at that sound and light tower?
我只是喜欢听音乐
I just liked listening to the music,
而且 前一天晚上 我把我妈妈带出来了
and, the night before, I got to bring my mama down.
我们都想听肯尼 罗杰斯的歌
We got to listen to Kenny Rogers.
她很喜欢 很好听
She liked that. That was nice.
我想这是一个很有利的位置
And I guess I also get a nice vantage point
可以看看在场所有的漂亮姑娘
to take a look at all the pretty girls.
毕竟我不是同性恋
I am not a homosexual.
大卫 杜契斯也不是
And neither is David Dutchess.
所以你和大卫 杜契斯并不是恋人关系
So you and David Dutchess are not lovers?
已经回答过了
Asked and answered.
朱维尔先生 你之前说过
Mr. Jewell, you said before
你在舞台和灯光塔之间
that in your comings and goings back and forth
往返的过程中
from the stage to the tower that you couldn't get, uh,
你无法得到一个准确的时间安排 是否属实
an exact fix on the time. Is that correct?
是的 但你忙起来的时候
Yes, but when you have the runs,
不好意思 应该说是我忙起来的时候
which I did, excuse me,
根本没有心思去想时间
You're not thinking about what time it is.
你只能尽力
You're just trying to
来回奔走
Crab-walk to a bathroom, you know?
也就是说 你不记得看见那些酗酒者
So you don't remember the exact time
朝灯光塔仍啤酒瓶的
that you saw the drunks
确切时间了
throwing the beer cans against the tower?
是这样吗
Right?
不是
No.
你不记得第一次见到那个背包的
You don't remember the exact time
确切时间
You first saw the backpack?
是的
That's correct.
你之前看到过类似背包吗 朱维尔先生
You ever seen a backpack like that before, Mr. Jewell?
是的 我猜是的
Yeah, I suppose so. Yeah.
那你之前看到过这个背包吗 朱维尔先生
You ever see that specific backpack before, Mr. Jewell?
已经答过了 可以跳过吗
Asked and answered. Can we move on?
朱维尔先生
Mr. Jewell,
你是否和大卫 杜契斯或者什么其他人
Did you conspire with David Dutchess or anybody else
合谋在世纪公园放置炸弹
to plant a bomb in centennial park?
没有
No.
那你他妈是怎么知道
Then how the fuck did you know
在AT&T 灯光塔的另一边
to be on the other side of that AT&T tower
能使你避开爆炸的伤害
where you knew you'd be protected from the blast?
有一枚炸弹在你驻扎的地方爆炸了
A bomb went off right where you were stationed.
混乱爆发 人们倒成一片
Chaos erupts. Bodies hit the ground.
警察受伤摔倒在地 见鬼 我就是其中一个
Cops go flying. Hell, I was one of them.
你却毫发未损
You come out without a goddamn scratch.
这怎么可能 理查德
How does that happen, Richard?
我能向你们在座所有人提一个问题吗
Can I ask all you fellas a question?
天呐 什么问题
Jesus. What?
你们发现了任何对我不利的事实吗
Do you have any kind of case against me?
我是说证据
I mean evidence.
比如 在我妈妈用的特百惠上发现了什么蛛丝马迹
Like, any traces of anything on my mama's tupperware?
又或者是在她的公寓发现了
Or did you find any bomb-making materials
任何制作炸弹的材料
in her apartment?
又或者你们找到一些
Or did you find some...
好了嘿
Okay. Hey, hey.
理查德 我们不需要
Richard, we don't need to volunteer...
不 如果我一定要说些什么的话 这个我一定要说出来
No. I'm gonna say this if I'm gonna say anything.
我进来的时候 看见
I walk in here and I look at...
你们这窗户上的圆形贴纸
The circle decal on your windows there,
我就在想
And I'm thinking...
我过去常常认为联邦执法部门
You know, I used to think that federal law enforcement
一个人向往的
was just about the highest calling
最高境界
a person could aspire to.
但我不确定我以后还会不会这么认为
And I'm not sure I think that anymore, you know?
在经历了这些事儿之后
Not after all this.
我在那晚完成我的工作
I did my job that night,
许多人因此获救
and some people are alive because of that.
但你觉得 下一次
But do you think that the next time
当有安保人员看到可疑包裹的时候
some security guard sees a suspicious package,
我严重怀疑
that he or she's gonna call it in?
他还会不会打电话
I doubt it.
因为他们要考虑一下
You know? 'Cause they're gonna look at that
然后他们会想
and they're gonna think,
我不想成为另一个理查德 朱维尔
"I don't wanna be another Richard Jewell.
所以我还是跑吧
So I'm just gonna run."
这样怎么会让人们更安全
How's that make anybody any safer?
你们可以继续盯着我
Y'all can keep following me around some more
继续你们现在的工作 我可以忍受
doing what you're doing. I can stand it.
但是我知道你们花在我身上的每一秒钟
But I just know that every second you spend on me
都本该用在
is time that you're not spending
揪出那个真正的犯人
on the real guy who did it,
就像沃森说的 如果
and it's like Watson said. What...
他再这样的话怎么
What happens when he...
他再这样的话怎么办
What happens when he does it again?
那么 你们想告我什么
So, do you have anything you wanna charge me with?
你们能告吗
Can you?
好
Well.
我想是时候走了
I think it's time to go.
他表现的怎么样
How'd he do?
他做的非常好
He did great.
天哪
God.
唔
Yeah.
进去吧
Go on.
- 嘿 - 两位
- Hey. - Gentlemen.
探员肖
Agent Shaw.
给你们带了东西
Got something for ya.
这是什么
What's this?
求婚信
Marriage proposal.
噢
Oh.
我的幸运日
My lucky day.
额
Uh...
好啊
Okay.
这是个好开头
Well, this is a good start.
新闻发布会是什么时候
When's the press conference?
我猜你们会对
I'm assuming you'll be announcing
所有大型新闻机构发布吧 汤姆·布罗考之类的
To all the news outlets, Tom Brokaw and the like.
布莱恩特先生 我说清楚
Mr. Bryant, let me be perfectly clear.
我还是觉得你的客户嫌疑非常大
I still think your client is guilty as hell.
唔
Hmm?
祝你愉快
Have a nice day.
你有权利这么想
Well, you're entitled to your opinion.
本函建议你们
"This is to advise you
基于证据
That based on the evidence..."
结束了
It's over.
真的结束了吗
Is it... is it really over,
还是又是他们的圈套
or is this just another one of their things?
你赢了 结束了
You won. It's over.
你很棒
You did good.
噢 我想见 我想见妈妈
Oh, I wanna see... I wanna see mama.
你想见你妈妈吗
You wanna see your mama?
嗯
Yeah.
可以的
We can do that.
这是真的吗
That's real?
上面是这么说的
That's what it says.
不作为
"not considered a target
联邦刑事调查
In the federal criminal investigation
有关1996年7月27日世纪公园爆炸案的
Of the bombing of July 27th, 1996,
的调查对象
Centennial park."
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
谢谢
Thank you.
没事儿
You got it.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
你好 沃森 布莱恩特
Hello, Watson Bryant.
嘿
Hey.
需要什么帮助吗
What can I do you for?
你还好吗 她
How are you? How's, uh...
天哪 娜德雅怎么样
My god, how's Nadya?
理查德 他们找到他了
They found him, Richard.
找到谁
Found who?
埃里克•鲁道夫
Eric Rudolph.
他供认了世纪公园的爆炸案
He confessed to the bombing at centennial park.
你知道他什么时候被传讯吗
You know when he's being arraigned?
不知道
I don't know.
能帮我打听一下吗
Can you find out for me?
瞧瞧你
Look at you.